嘿 桑尼 五分钟
Hey, Sonny. Five minutes.
戴通纳24小时耐力赛
晚11点56分
桑尼!
Sonny!
嘿 宝马车队的人在那边抱怨刹车问题
Hey. BMW guys are over therebitching about brake trouble.
谢了 莫莉 你最棒了
Thanks, Molly. You're a superstar.
赛场上见
I'll see you out there.
圈数
我才打了个盹就这样了
Turn my back for one minute.
我们崩盘了 桑尼
It's all gone to shit, Sonny.
帕特不得不减速
Pat had to ease off.
我们掉到第七了
We've dropped down to seventh.
你现在只要保住名次 熬过今晚
If you can just hold position overnight,
说不定天一亮 我们就能迎来转机
hopeful sunrise catches us a break.
桑尼 注意高速时保持车身平衡...
Sonny, watch that high-speed balance.
车身平衡!
High-speed balance!
变速箱怎么样?
How's the gearbox?
还撑得住 但动作放轻点
It's holding up, but go easy.
观众虽然回家了
The crowds may have gone home,
但比赛仍在继续
but the racing continues.
桑尼·海耶斯回到了Peak Geico Chip Hart Racing车队的保时捷上
Sonny Hayes back in the Porsche for Peak Geico Chip Hart Racing.
午夜轮班开始了
The midnight shift.
众所周知 海耶斯...
We all know Hayes
喜欢让夜晚燥起来
likes to light up the night,
但眼下领跑的是宝马车队
but with the BMW at the head of this pack,
他想赶超实属不易
he's got a massive job ahead of him.
刚一入场
Right out of the gate
海耶斯就穿针引线般切入三号弯
Hayes threads the needle into turn three,
跃升到第四
moving up to fourth place.
桑尼 还是在直道超车吧?
Sonny, wanna maybe pass on the straights?
别对我指手画脚 行吗?
Just let me drive, will ya?
注意
Look out.
12号赛车的引擎出故障了
Engine trouble for the number 12.
海耶斯再上升一位
That moves Hayes up another spot.
老天啊 还有十小时呢
Sweet baby Jesus. We got ten more hours.
让桑尼按自己的方式开吧
Just let Sonny do his thing.
开始这几圈至少说明了一个问题
And if these first few laps are any indication,
桑尼·海耶斯好像把刹车踏板落在家里了
it appears as though Sonny Hayes may have left his brake pedal at home.
海耶斯盯住了宝马
Hayes sets his sights on the BMW.
他发动攻击了
And he attacks.
海耶斯来到了外线
Here comes Hayes on the outside.
加油啊 桑尼
Come on, Sonny.
宝马刹车刹晚了
The BMW late on the brakes.
他上草了
He's in the grass.
海耶斯能稳住吗?
Can Hayes hang on?
他成功了
And he does.
厉害
Goddamn!
看见没有?这才叫赛车
See that? That's how you race, boys.
到你们上场的时候
When you get back in that car,
都给我照这样开
you need to do the same goddamn thing.
桑尼·海耶斯在完成了精彩绝伦的第三棒后
Sonny Hayes brings it
进入维修区
into pit lane after an epic third stint
他已成功将Chip Hart Racing车队带到了领先位置
that puts Chip Hart Racing out in front.
现在要看卡尔·凯尔索能否守住位置了
Now, it's up to Cale Kelso to hang on to that lead.
谢了 老大 你帮我们开了个好头
Thanks for the head start, Chief.
嘿 你要是落后了 我就杀了你
Hey. Lose that lead, I'll kill ya.
海耶斯!
Hayes!
嘿 混蛋!
Hey, dirtbag!
-竟敢把我逼下赛道  -算了 不值得
-Gonna run me off the track, Hayes?  -It's not worth it.
你以为我不知道上哪找你吗?
You think I don't know where to find you?
-算了  -去你*的
-It's not worth it.  -Screw you!
撒手
Let go of me!
嘿 好样的 桑尼
Hey. Attaboy, Sonny.
谢谢 如果我们输了 就别叫醒我
Thanks. Don't wake me if we lose.
桑尼·海耶斯
Sonny Hayes,
你是不是忘了点什么?
I believe you forgot something.
我的包装满了 奇普
Bag's full, Chip.
不是吧?
Seriously?
你在戴通纳的第一场胜利
Your first win at Daytona.
你连碰都不碰一下?
Don't you even want to touch it?
-来嘛  -会惹霉运
-Come on.  -Bad luck.
-摸一下嘛  -不了 不了
-Just touch it.  -No. Hey.
不过奖金可不能少了我的
I will take that bonus check, though.
桑尼... 听我说
Sonny. Sonny! Just hear me out.
听着 我想招你入队
Look, I wanna bring you on board.
你现在是奇普车队的一员了
You're CHR family now.
明年此地 我们再赢一次
Right here, next year, let's run it back.
兄弟 我们成功了 合约结束
We did it, man. Deal's a deal.
我当然知道
I know what a deal is.
就这样了?一锤子买卖?
So that's it? One and done?
感谢你让我参赛 奇普
I appreciate the seat, Chip.
真心的
I really do.
这算什么比赛方式啊?
What kind of way is that to race?
你这辈子简直就是一直在重新开始啊 兄弟
You just spend your whole life starting over, man.
你保重吧
You take care.
后会有期
I'll see you down the road.
嘿 你不要手表吗?
Hey! Don't you want the watch?
我有一块了
Got one!
WHOG, Ormond-by-the-Sea.
WHOG 滨海奥蒙德
Proud to be locally owned.
由本地经营
A Southern Stone station.
来自南石电台
The world's most famous rock
全球最有名的摇滚
from the world's most famous beach
来自全球最有名的海滩
we are
我们是
Daytona's rock station
戴通纳摇滚电台
ninety-five seven, the Hog
95.7 HOG电台
诚邀车手
巴哈1000
恩塞纳达       下加利福尼亚             墨西哥
不好意思 请问 能借用一下你的手机吗?
Sorry, can I use your phone for a second, please?
我的坏了
It's not working.
不能
No.
你让我想起了以前的一位朋友
You know, you remind me of this friend I used to have.
什么朋友?
Which friend?
衣品比你好的朋友
Friend who dressed better.
这西装是古驰的
This is a Gucci suit.
我这件也是
So's this.
你朋友是干什么的?
What did your friend do?
开车的
Drove cars.
-开得快吗?  -不慢
-Was he fast?  -Wasn't slow.
-他赢过吗?  -赢过
-Did he win?  -Yeah, he did.
来抱一个 小子
Come here, you son of a bitch.
天啊
Oh, God.
你想参加巴哈?
Are you thinking Baja?
对 新的一天 新的挑战
Yeah. New day, new challenge.
这正是我当初买下APX GP车队时 对自己说的话
That's exactly what I said to myself  when I bought APX GP.
你亏了多少?
How deep in the hole are you?
可以告诉你 但你不许笑
I'll tell you,but you have to promise not to laugh.
说吧
Shoot.
3.5
亿
million.
别笑
Don't laugh.
你可真厉害
Impressive.
至少开心过吧?
Well, been fun?
是的 那当然
Yeah. Absolutely.
出了什么问题呢?
What's the problem then?
问题是两个半赛季
Problem is two seasons and a half,
零积分
zero points.
我最厉害的车手去了另一支车队
My best driver left for another team.
他说我们的赛车是一坨垃圾
He said the car was a shitbox.
车队排在最后一名
The team is in last place.
我的二号车手是个菜鸟
My number two's a rookie.
而且赛季已经过半
And the season's half over.
-还剩多少场?  -九场
-How many races left?  -Nine.
如果我们不能逆袭 我会失去车队
And if we don't turn it around, I lose the team.
什么?
What?
可是车队是你的啊
But you own the team.
前三个赛季一场未赢
No race wins in your first three seasons,
董事会可以强行出售车队
the board can force a sale.
哥们 听起来你需要一个新董事会
Man, sounds like you need a new board.
我需要一个新车手
I need a new driver.
你有F2、F3
You got F2. You got F3.
还有一整代在模拟器里成长起来的年轻车手
You got an entire assembly line of kids raised on the simulator.
不 我没那个时间去教一个毛头小子怎么争第十名 真没有
No, I don't have time for some kid to learn how to come in tenth. I don't.
但你不能随便从街上拉个人就去开火箭啊
Well, you don't just walk off the street and pilot a rocket.
可以 如果以前开过就可以 这是重点
Yes, you can if you've done it before.That's the whole point.
路易·希龙赢得摩纳哥大奖赛时都57岁了
Louis Chiron was 57 years old when he won the Monaco Grand Prix.
-路易什么?  -菲利普·埃唐瑟兰 56岁
1Louis who?  -Philippe Étancelin, 56 years old.
这都是你刚从网上搜的吧?
You just Googled these names, didn't you?
在有些人眼里 桑尼·海耶斯
Some people look at Sonny Hayes,
只是个睡在面包车里的家伙
they see a guy who lives in a van,
一个错过机会的赌徒
a gambling junkie who missed his shot.
天啊 鲁本 你可真有说服力
Wow, Ruben, you are really selling this.
但在我眼里 他能提升一个车队的实力
But I see a guy who makes teams better.
他经验老道、实力非凡
I see experience. I see know-how.
你脑子进水了
You're off your meds.
我的新车手才华横溢 堪称天才 但他很年轻
My rookie's a phenomenal talent. Phenomenal. But he's young.
知道他缺少什么吗?成熟
You know what he lacks? Maturity.
你加上他?
You plus him?
这车队不就成了吗
Boom. I got a team.
好吧 就说我是下一个路易...
All right. Let's say I'm the next Louis...
仅限车手取餐
-希龙  -就是他
Chiron. -Him.
仅限车手取餐
问题不光是车手 还有车啊
The problem is it's not just the driver, it's the car.
这个赛季我一直关注着你 鲁本
I've followed your season, Ruben.
"破烂货"都说得太婉转了
"Shitbox" is being kind.
我就知道你在看
I knew you were watching.
如果这个周末 我们能拿到升级套件 你会怎么想?
What if I told you we get an upgrade package this weekend?
-开发了六个月的...  -鲁本
-Six months in development...  -Ruben...
不...听我说完
No, no, no. Wait.
我只需要车队里的一辆车 率先冲线
I just need one of my cars across the finish line first.
一辆就行
One.
我们是好兄弟 但我不会回去了
I love ya. I'm not going back.
好吧
Okay.
F1新星
桑尼·海耶斯和鲁本·塞万提斯
他会希望你怎么做?
What would he want you to do?
加入男团吗?
Join a boy band?
说真的 拜托
Seriously. Come on.
说真的 我想问他:"你笑什么笑?"
Seriously, I'd ask him what he's smiling about.
别这样
Come on.
他笑是因为梦想有可能成真
He's smiling at the possibility.
可后来结果如何 你我心知肚明
We both know how that ended.
是的
Yep.
好吧
Okay.
-这是去伦敦的头等舱机票  -天啊
-This is a first-class ticket to London.  -Oh, my God.
头等舱哦
First class.
我给你提供一个F1的席位
I'm offering you an open seat in Formula 1.
只有在这里获胜 你才能说
The only place you could say for one day,
你是全世界最好的车手
if you win, you are the absolute best in the world.
嘿 鲁本
Hey, Ruben.
-你见过奇迹吗?  -还没有
-Ever seen a miracle?  -Not yet.
我也没有
Me neither.
见到你很高兴 朋友
Good to see you, amigo.
-好 亲爱的 你的餐  -谢谢
-All right, sweetie, here you go.  -Thank you.
嘿 问你件事
Hey, let me ask you something.
一个很要好的朋友给了你一个
Close friend of yours made you an offer
"百分百、绝对好得离谱"的工作
that was 100%, positively
好到不真实
too good to be true.
你会怎么办?
What do you do?
给多少钱呢?
Well, how much are we talking?
钱不是重点
Not about the money.
那重点是什么?
So what is it about?
奥兰多国际机场
伦敦希思罗机场
头等舱
胎温正常 前85 后75
Tire temps look good. Eighty-five front, Seventy-five rear.
-可以推进  -收到
-You are good to push.  -Copy.
电充满了 可以切换到模式二
Battery is full. You're good for strat two.
推进一圈
Going for a lap.
第一计时段刷紫 是你的最佳成绩
Purple sector one. Your best one yet.
车况很好
Car feels good.
见鬼
Damn!
刹车锁死了 左前胎出现平斑
Locked it up. Flat spot, front left.
叫他回来
Bring him in.
切换到模式一
Go to strat one.
本圈进站...
Box this lap. Box this lap.
来查查问题出在哪吧
Let's go find those gremlins.
皮尔斯
抱歉 约书亚
Sorry, Joshua.
乔蒂 别把我们的车手撞死了
Jodie, try not to kill our driver.
有结论了吗?
What's the verdict?
不知道怎么回事 赛车状况良好 我开始推进
I don't know what's happening. I mean, it feels good. I start to push.
然后在低速弯它转向不足 在高速弯又转向过度
Then it understeers in the slow corners and oversteers the fast.
什么?进弯还是出弯?
What? On entries or exits?
都没有 都有
Either. Both.
行吧
Great. Yeah.
这车上装了一万个感应器 你还不知道出了什么问题
There's 10,000 sensors on this thing and you can't tell me what's going on.
但开车的又不是我 对吧?
But I'm not out there, am I?
所以你得帮帮我 拜托
So, I'm gonna need your help on this. Please.
一亿五千万美元的攀登架
150 million dollar jungle gym.
好可爱
So cute.
应该让她开车 也差不到哪去
We should let her drive. Can't be any worse.
约书亚
Joshua.
-嗨  -利斯贝思 公关部的
-Hi.  -Lisbeth. PR?
-是  -没关系
-Oh, yeah.  -Doesn't matter.
对于这次新闻发布会 我们希望避开技术层面的问题
For the press conference, we want to steer around tech issues
重点谈你和新队友卢卡·科尔特斯之间超强的默契
and focus on the super strong bond with your new teammate, Luca Cortez.
卢卡?
Luca?
那位我刚认识一周
Who I've known a week.
之前在红牛车队当三号替补车手
Who when he was third banana on the left at Red Bull,
就跟媒体说约书亚·皮尔斯被捧得过高
told the press he thought Joshua Pearce was overrated.
是这个卢卡·科尔特斯吗?
That Luca Cortez?
是的
Yes.
-等不及了呢  -好 太好了 谢谢
1Can't wait. Yeah.  1All right. Great. Thank you.
唷
Yo.
你答应了?是吗?
That's a yes? Yeah? Yes?
怎么样?
What's up?
唷 你说对了 兄弟
Yo, you were right, bro.
鲁本遇到大麻烦了 他可能会卖掉车队
Ruben's in big trouble.He might have to sell the team.
我就知道
I knew it.
我会怎么样呢?
And what does that mean for me?
新的买家可能会给车队大换血
New buyers, they're likely to clean house.
听着
Listen.
伙计 你得让这些人见识见识 谁才是真正的头号车手
You need to show these people who the number one driver really is, man.
就现在
Now.
否则你会丢饭碗的
Or you're gonna lose your job.
是的 你想想吧
Yeah. Let that sink in.
嗨
Hey.
快走...
Shoo, shoo.
还好吗?
You good?
好 让我们把前半个赛季
Okay, let's take the first half of the season
从脑子里抹去吧
and erase it from our minds.
有人问:"卡什帕 今年怎么了?"
Someone says, "Kaspar, what happened this year?"
我以孩子们的性命发誓 我不知道
I swear on the lives of my children, I do not freaking know.
现在只剩下这辆车
There's only this car.
以及我们的未来
And there is only our future.
是的 我们的未来
Yes. Our future.
那个混蛋是谁?
Who is that asshole?
是我的人
He's with me.
你的人以为我是维修工 把我指到后门去了
Your man thought I was maintenance. Sent me to the back gate.
兄弟 你从不让我失望啊
Brother, you have never let me down.
话别说得太早了
Well, there's still time.
APX GP车队
APX GP!
桑尼·海耶斯 他当年跟我一起赛过车
Sonny Hayes. He raced with me back in the day.
-是跟你当对手  -对
1Against you, you mean.  -Yeah.
-凯特·麦克纳 技术总监  -嗨
-Kate McKenna, our technical director.  -Hi.
-道奇·多达 首席机械师  -嗨
-Dodge Dauda, our chief mechanic.  -Hi.
还有 卡什帕·斯莫林斯基 车队领队
And Kaspar Smolinski, team principal.
你可能听过他的大名
You may know him by reputation.
和法拉利一起5次夺得车队总冠军
Five-time Constructors champion with Ferrari.
作为后千斤顶机械师
As a rear jack man.
我爸也是 没有你们可赢不了比赛
So was my pop. Can't win without 'em.
-还有才华横溢的新手 约书亚  -他为什么带了个头盔?
-And our talented rookie, Joshua.  -Why has he got a helmet?
为了安全啊
Safety?
约书亚 放心 你的车手席位很稳
Joshua, your seat is safe. Okay?
桑尼是来面试的
Sonny is here for the audition.
你上次赢得比赛是什么时候?
When was the last time you won a race?
星期天 戴通纳
Sunday. Daytona.
不好意思 我是说F1
I'm sorry. I meant Formula 1.
不好意思 那和你一样
Oh, I'm sorry. Then same as you.
天啊
Wow.
没想到我会这么问 有谁看见卢卡·科尔特斯了吗?
Never thought I'd say this, has anyone seen Luca Cortez?
请单独谈谈 鲁本
Sidebar bitte, Ruben.
我跟你面试的时候 很多老车手...
When I interview with you, many veteran drivers-
对 都把你拒了
Yeah, who all turned you down.
-多少个?  -七个
-How many?  -Seven.
-真不少  -我是第七个?
-That's a lot.  -I'm number seven?
你是第八个
You're eight.
真是灾难
This is a disaster.
我感觉自己更像第九个了
I'm starting to feel more like a nine.
严格来说 有一位车手还没给我答复
Technically, there is one who I've not heard from yet.
所以我就是第九个?
So I am a nine?
你识数吧?
You know how numbers work, right?
做生意的时候 我最好的点子总是很晚才出现
In business, my most inspired ideas come late.
是啊 人生中最美好的东西 往往第九个到来 对吧?
Yeah. Best things in life usually arrive ninth, right?
恕我直言 鲁本 我不同意用仅有的测试日
With respect, Ruben, I cannot condone we spend our only test day
来给你失联已久的队友做面试
giving your long-lost teammate an audition.
卡什帕 你误会了
Kaspar, you misunderstand.
不是我们面试他 是他面试我们
We're not auditioning him. He's auditioning us.
那是新车手
That's your new driver.
祝你好运
Good luck.
新的前翼和侧箱
New wing, new side pods.
底板有调整吗?
Any changes to the floor?
都是其他八个车手能看出来的改动
Nothing the eight other drivers wouldn't have figured out.
所以我人称"幸运九号"
That's why they call me Lucky Number Nine.
听着 你好久没在这里赛车了 朋友 对吗?
Listen, it's been a while since you've driven here, mate. Yeah?
这些赛车的平衡很难搞 所以一号、九号弯要小心
The balance on these cars are tricky, so be careful turn one and nine.
我可不想看到你受伤
Wouldn't want to see you get hurt.
我们设定个合理的目标吧?
How about we set a reasonable target?
给我按他的调校改车 如果我的圈速不能在JP的一秒以内
Give me the same setup as him. If I can't post a lap time within a second of JP's,
那我马上自己滚蛋
then I will promptly see myself out
你们尽管把机会给幸运十号好了
and you're free to take a shot at lucky number ten.
-十号?  -十号
-Ten?  -Ten.
十号
Ten.
JP是谁?
Who's JP?
过Brooklands(6号弯)要切内线过去 Luffield(7号弯)弯稳住节奏
Cross round on Brooklands, easy on Luffield.
一口气冲到Woodcote(8号弯)，Copse(9号弯)弯要全油门出弯
Up to Woodcote, hard out in Copse.
弯中要小心
And be careful on the curve.
保持默认模式下 模式一、二、三 依次切换
Default mode, settings one, to two, back to three.
差速器从一到四
Differential one through four.
DRS.
好 看看你的性能吧
Okay. Let's see what you got.
如果他和鲁本赛过车 那就是和舒马赫 还有塞纳也比赛过
If he raced with Ruben, he raced with Schumacher. With Senna.
OK 把约书亚的计时段成绩调出来
All right, pull up Joshua's sector times.
我赌20英镑 他会一败涂地
Twenty quid says he stacks it.
我赌100 来吧
Make it a hundred, you're on.
该死
Oh, shit.
抱歉 我是休尼·克尔贝 比赛工程师
Sorry, this is Hugh Nickleby, your race engineer.
早上好 休 胎温是多少?
Good morning, Hugh. How are my tire temps looking?
好 差不多可以了 这圈结束可以全力冲刺了
Yep, almost warm. End of the lap, you should be good to push.
行吧 哥们
Right. Man.
-休  -在 先生
-Hugh?  -Yes, sir?
你真该接受刚才的赌注了
You should've taken that bet.
收到
Copy that.
准备单圈计时
Going for a lap.
不好
Nope.
该死
Shit.
他完蛋了
He's dead.
拜托 别这样
Come on. Don't do that.
死透了
And buried.
别急
Wait.
稳住
就是现在
Now.
赛车状态良好 加油
The car is there, come on.
他的成绩赶上来了
He's gaining.
不好
Ah, shit.
你没事吧?
You okay?
没事 一切正常
Yep. All good.
银石赛道
这车有点问题
Yeah, she's got something.
你是说"曾经"有吧
Yeah, you mean had something.
高速转向过于灵敏
But definitely snappy in the high-speed corners.
低速弯里又非常不稳
Unpredictable in the lows.
第14、16号弯 车尾有问题
Had trouble with the rears, turns 14, 16
也许还有最后一个弯吧?
And the final turn, maybe?
不 最后那个怪我
No, that's on me.
他的圈速是多少?
What was his lap time?
他通过了自己给自己设定的圈速
He passed his entirely self-imposed test,
以五百分之一秒的优势
by five hundredths of a second.
好吧
Well...
至少迈出第一步了
it's a start.
兄弟 我们要用九场比赛
Bro, we got nine races
来吸引其他车队的注意
to catch the eye of another team, you know.
身为你的经纪人 我必须提醒你
And as your manager, I have to advise you
我们得开始参加社交和赞助商活动了
that we need to start hitting these social and sponsor events.
约书亚 你的社媒得提高互动率 要涨粉
You need more engagement, Josh, more followers.
-好 一言为定  -好的 我就是说说而已
-All right, deal.  -All right, cool. I'm just saying, innit?
你吃饭了吗? 我有点饿
You eaten? I'm starving.
还没
Nah.
不过我得去见个人
Gotta see someone though.
是吗? 拍张照片 发个帖子
Yeah? Hey, take a picture, post that shit.
发给我 我来发
Send it to me, I'll post that shit.
是我妈
It's my mum.
那绝对不许发
Don't you dare post that shit.
我就知道你会这么说
I knew you was gonna say that.
皮尔斯有麻烦了?
宝贝 还好吗?
Okay, baby?
还行 就是有点累
Yeah. Just tired.
轮胎爆了还是引擎坏了?
Bad tires or the engine?
行了 妈 你对赛车一无所知
Come on, Mum. You don't know about the cars.
没大没小的
Facety.
我虽然不太了解赛车 但我很了解你
All right, I may not know much about cars, but I know a lot about you.
说吧
Go.
如果车队赢不了比赛 我可能会失去席位
I might lose my seat if the team don't win a race.
随便赢一场比赛就行
Any race.
其他车队呢?
There are other teams?
有20个席位 但都有人了
Yeah, there's 20 seats, but they're all filled.
而且有个新人 他...
Plus, there's this new guy, and...
年纪很大
he's old.
多大岁数?
How old?
非常大 差不多...80
Like, really old. Like... 80.
他是个混蛋 妈
He's such an arsehole, Mum.
但车开得很快
He's quick, though.
别管那些
Don't mind that.
专注于自己
Focus on you.
你大可以用一辈子去担心别人的事
You can spend your whole life worrying about other people,
但是当下是属于你的
but your time is right now.
你还热爱赛车吗?
You still love it?
当然热爱
Course I still love it.
那就记着你父亲说过的话
Then, remember what your father used to say.
"专心开车"
"Put your head down and drive."
是 女士
Yes, ma'am.
逗我呢吧
You're kiddin' me.
我以为你的工作是打造全世界最快的赛车
Thought your job was to build the fastest car on the planet.
我的工作是研究风
My job is wind.
所以亲身感受是有必要的
So, helps to feel it.
APX GP车队动向神秘
Mysterious moves at APX GP,
他们终于公布了
who have finally announced the driver
将出任其二号车手席位的人选
who will take their second seat.
不可思议的是
And in a bizarre twist,
此人竟是美国车手 桑尼·海耶斯
it's American Sonny Hayes,
他已经30多年
who hasn't raced in Formula 1
没参加过 F1 比赛了
for over three decades.
海耶斯是印地赛车机械师的儿子
Son of an IndyCar mechanic,
年轻时曾被视为鲁莽的奇才
Hayes was considered something
of a reckless young phenomenon,
但从来没问鼎过顶级大赛
the greatest who never was.
他原本的职业生涯因在西班牙大奖赛上
His former career being brought to an abrupt halt
遭遇的一场惨烈事故而戛然而止
by a horrific accident at the Spanish Grand Prix.
十年后
He reappeared a decade later
他再次出现在各种赛车运动中
in racing championships
勒芒24小时、纳斯卡、达喀尔拉力赛
as diverse as Le Mans, NASCAR, the Dakar Rally
甚至还在纽约开过一段时间的出租车
and even a stint as a New York taxi driver.
不
Oh, no.
但现在他却为一支车队重出江湖 这支车队
But now he's back racing for a team which has,
在其整个F1历史中从未进入过前十
in its entire F1 history, never even finished in the top ten.
这一切都不会减少外界
None of this will dampen speculation
对于大股东塞万提斯
that majority shareholder Cervantes Capital
有意出售车队的猜测
are looking to sell the team.
如果他们真的出售车队 这很可能会
And if they do, that will likely also bring an end
终结F1新人约书亚·皮尔斯的职业生涯
to the career of F1 rookie Joshua Pearce.
我们能走了吗?
Can we go now?
常言道:
Desperate times,they say,
"非常时期要用非常手段"
"call for desperate measures,"
但我真的不记得有谁
but I honestly cannot recall a driver signing
会如此仓促地签合同
quite as desperate as this.
走吧
Let's go.
好家伙 看看我儿子
Boy, look at my son.
嘿
Hey.
就是这位
That's the one.
这就是另一位车手?
That's the other driver?
对 就是这张蠢脸
Yep. That's him and his stupid face.
但是 等等 你说他很老 也没那么老嘛
But, wait, you said he was old. He not that old.
嘿 约书亚
Hey, Josh.
你想出人头地吗?
You want a next shot anywhere?
九场比赛 就是说 你必须战胜"查克·诺里斯"九次
Nine races means nine times you have to beat Chuck Norris.
现在 先从赢得媒体青睐开始吧
For now, start by winning over the press.
好吗?准备好了吗?
Yeah? You ready?
好 走吧
Cool. Let's go.
这人很帅啊
That's a handsome man right there.
约书亚 你好 不可否认 这个赛季开局不利
Joshua. Hey. It's been an undeniably messy start to your season.
未尝一胜 赛车状况频出 你现在又有了一位新队友
No wins, car problems throughout, and now you have another new teammate.
你感觉如何?
How exactly are you finding it?
开局不利不等于无法笑到最后 对吧?
Messy start doesn't mean you can't finish neat. All right?
APX拥有优秀的工程师团队 我有信心能翻盘
APX have a fire crew of engineers, so I'm confident we'll come back fightin'.
至于新队友
In terms of new teammates,
我觉得APX能给老人再就业的机会挺好的
I think it's really wonderful that APX are giving second chances to the elderly.
好 下一个问题 谢谢，好的 唐 请问吧
Yes. Next question. Thank you. Yes, Don. Yeah.
海耶斯先生 你好 我是唐·卡文迪许 欢迎回到英国
Mr. Hayes. Hi. Don Cavendish. Welcome back to the UK.
好久没来过了 是吧?
It's been a while, mmm?
你上次在银石赛道比赛时
I mean, last time you raced at Silverstone,
克林顿还是总统 最火的舞是玛卡雷娜
Bill Clinton was your president, and we were all dancing the Macarena.
回来的感觉一定很不真实吧
So it must be surreal to be back.
是
Yeah.
十年之间 你放弃了赛车
And during that decade, you gave up racing,
当了一名职业赌徒?
and gambled professionally?
Uh-huh.
然后宣布破产?
Before declaring yourself personally bankrupt?
Yep.
一段婚姻被宣告无效 还有两次以离婚收场?
You had a marriage annulled and two more ended in divorce?
Yep.
有后悔过吗?
Anything you wish you'd done differently?
Yeah.
提问结束 谢谢，好的 谢谢大家
No more questions. Thank you. Yes. Thank you.
嗨 道奇
Yes, Dodge.
他什么时候来的?
What time was he here?
比我早
Before me.
也比你早
And before you.
好 他来了 道歉吧
Okay, here he comes. Apologize.
道歉?做不到
Apologize? I can't do that.
-什么意思?为什么?  -因为道歉是软弱的表现
-How you mean? Why not?  -Because it's a sign of weakness.
是强大的表现
It's a sign of strength.
软弱的表现
Sign of weakness.
你真顽固 道歉就是了
You hard ears, just do it.
妈 我做不到
Mum, I can't.
你做得到 必须道歉
You can. You will.
嗨 哥们
Hey, man.
新闻发布会那天 我说的话多有冒犯
Other day at the press conference, stuff I said wasn't cool.
去道歉
You say sorry.
所以我是想说...抱歉
So, basically what I'm trying to say is...I'm sorry.
没关系 你只是担心 我开得比你快，嗨 我叫桑尼
It's all right. You're just worried I'm quicker than you. Hi, I'm Sonny.
伯纳黛特·皮尔斯 幸会
Bernadette Pearce. Nice to meet you.
幸会 没关系的 赛道上见
Pleasure.It's all good. I'll see you out there.
感觉怎么样?
How are you feeling?
-非常好  -好
-So good.  -Good.
-你还好吗?  -很好
-You good?  -Good.
好
Good.
别有压力
No pressure.
没压力
None.
-很好  -很好
-Great.  -Great.
很好
Great.
欢迎来到银石赛道
Welcome along to Silverstone,
英国大奖赛
银石赛道
1950年5月13日
the circuit where on the 13th of May 1950
F1在此赛道拉开帷幕
the Formula 1 World Championship began.
今天 在第77届英国大奖赛上
Today, we kick off the final nine races
我们将拉开本赛季最后九场
of this thrilling championship season
激动人心的冠军争夺战
here at the 77th British Grand Prix.
11支车队参赛
As always, 11 teams will take the grid,
每队派出两名车手
fielding two drivers each.
比赛发车顺序
With race order determined by
由昨天的排位赛成绩决定
the qualifying times set yesterday.
红牛车队(维斯塔潘)杆位发车
Red Bull will start on pole
紧随其后的是两位迈凯伦车手
followed by the two McLarensand
和两位法拉利车手
two Ferraris.
各位车手
Drivers,
两分钟后奏国歌
two minutes to national anthem.
桑尼
Sonny!
鲁本 别逼我和投资人说话
Ruben. Don't make me talk to the money.
来嘛 占用你一点时间 微笑着握手即可
Come on, give me a moment. Just smile and shake hands.
他是董事会里的重要成员
He's an important member of the board.
桑尼 这位是彼得·班宁
Sonny, this is Peter Banning,
-我的投资人之一  -嗨
-one of my investors.  -Hi.
嗨
Hi.
他对赛车一窍不通
He knows absolutely nothing about racing...
-是的  -但他是我在董事会里的眼线
-Yeah.  -...but he's my eyes and ears on the board.
你是鲁本孤注一掷的希望
And you're Ruben's Hail Mary.
这个说法来自美式橄榄球 对吧?
Now, that is an American football term, right?
孤注一掷的长传 就是...
The Hail Mary, the long shot. The...
我相信它最初来自宗教用语
I believe it's a religious term, originally.
是的...
That is true. That is true.
我在向诸神祈祷 我是...
I'm praying to them all. I'm a...
我是董事会里真心想保住车队的人
Yeah, I'm the one guy on the board who actually wants to keep the team.
其他人都说车队是"鲁本的炼狱"
The rest are calling it, you know, Ruben's Inferno.
但是说真的 哥们 我很感兴趣
But, seriously, man, I'm hooked.
我一口气刷完了《疾速争胜》
I've binged all of Drive to Survive.
我现在对轮胎的了解达到了空前的高度 太不可思议了
I honestly don't think I've ever known so much about car tires. It's incredible.
我去干本职工作了
I'm gonna get back to my day job.
-好 保重  -好
-Okay. Take care.  -Okay.
嘿 哥们 我们指望着你呢 祝好运
Hey, man. We're counting on you. Good luck.
桑尼 你在这里干吗呢?
What are you doing here, Sonny?
2023 一级方程式阿美石油英国大奖赛
随着时钟指向整点
And as the clock ticks then to the top of the hour,
比赛开始了
it's time to get things going here at Silverstone.
首先是暖胎圈
It's formation lap first.
绕赛道一圈
One tour of the track
让车手把轮胎和刹车温度提起来
and a chance for the driver s to warm up their tires and brakes.
不好 APX GP车队遇到问题了
Oh, no. There's a problem for APX.
排在22位的海耶斯还没有动
That's Hayes in P22. His car hasn't moved.
等等 我遇到动力问题了
Hang on. I got power trouble.
是启动模式 桑尼
It's start mode, Sonny.
打开启动模式
Start mode on.
是的 大家都记住了
Yes, a lesson for everyone at home.
新车再好 也要先看看说明书
New car? Do read the manual.
他已经很久没上赛道了
It's been a while since he was out on the track.
这样下去...
At this rate...
老天啊
Dios mío. Ay.
他甚至可能无法参赛
...he's not even gonna get into the race.
搞定了
I got it.
好了
All good.
他终于发车了
And he's away at last.
谢天谢地
Thank goodness for that.
如果他在暖胎圈落后太多
If he falls too far behind on the formation lap...
-喝一杯?  -不了
-Drink?  1No.
可能会被迫
he'll be at risk...
从维修区起步
of having to start in the pit lane.
桑尼在哪?他在拖累我们
Where's Sonny? He's holding us up.
好了 约书亚 我们正在看...
Yeah. Just checking, Joshua. Just checking.
-他的车怎么了?  -什么?什么也没有啊
-What's wrong with his car?  -What? Nothing.
前方赛道很空旷
With a clear track ahead,
海耶斯可以在暖胎圈开得更猛
Hayes has been able to push much harder、on this formation lap.
当他来到发车格
He'll turn up at the back of the grid
带着更暖的轮胎 开始起跑
with warm tires, ready to go.
无耻的混蛋 他故意的
Cheeky shit. It's on purpose.
这人想干什么?
What is this guy doing?
现在桑尼·海耶斯
This is actually now turning into an advantage
反倒有了优势
for Sonny Hayes.
并且刚好赶上
And he's just made it in time.
要小心他的起步了
Watch out for his start.
五盏红灯依次亮起
Five lights ahead of the drivers.
五盏红灯熄灭 比赛开始
It's lights out and away we go!
桑尼·海耶斯来了 女士们、先生们
Here comes Sonny Hayes, ladies and gentlemen.
利用更暖的轮胎
Using those warm tires,
从后方杀出重围
to carve his way through the back of the field.
如果有哪个赛道最需要你对赛车有信心
And if you ever need confidence in your car,
那一定就是银石赛道
it's here at Silverstone.
海耶斯快速超越诸多车手
Hayes is just sailing past people.
起步后 他已经上升了七个名次
He's moved up seven places since the start.
APX GP车队的这辆车之前故障连连
APX GP has struggled with this car
Yes!
但这个周末 他们安装了升级套装
...but they've brought an upgrade package this weekend.
让我们看看到底有没有用
Let's see if it makes a difference
桑尼向红牛车队的佩雷兹
as Hayes attacks Perez
发起了攻击
in the Red Bull.
赛车在乱流里颠簸不稳 我没法进攻
Car's bouncing around this dirty air. I can't position to attack.
海耶斯在无线电上抱怨他的车
Hayes complaining about his car over the radio.
这可不是车队想听的话
That's not what the team wants to hear.
收到 距离佩雷兹0.9秒 已进入DRS区间
Copy. Gap is 0.9 to Perez. You're within DRS range.
下一段直道应该可以超过他
Should be able to take him on the next straight.
海耶斯利用DRS超车了
Hayes now using the drag reduction system to get past.
Yeah!
我没法挡他 各位 我没有抓地力
Won't be able to hold him off, guys. I got no grip.
不是吧
Oh, come on.
现在APX GP车队有麻烦了
This is trouble now for APX GP.
红牛的轮胎暖起来了
The Red Bull's tires are now warm
海耶斯已经没有了
and Hayes hasn't got his tire advantage
轮胎优势
from the start anymore.
刚刚的进攻我们已经见识过了
We've seen the attack.
现在就看他守得如何
Now it's all about defense.
佩雷兹在Vale(16号弯)前发起了攻击
And Perez on the attack into Vale.
海耶斯有麻烦了
Hayes is in trouble.
二人的位置可能对调
This could be the places reversed.
确实如此
And it is.
该死
Damn.
车尾很不稳定 告诉我解决办法
Rear end is loose. Tell me if you see a fix.
告诉他延迟入弯 争取更好的出弯速度
Tell him to pull back the entry to get a better exit.
他以为是赛车调校问题 其实不是
He thinks it's the setup. It's not.
第20圈
比赛进行到第20圈
Twenty laps down,
维斯塔潘领跑
Verstappen leads
约书亚·皮尔斯
but Joshua Pearce
在赛道上的很挣扎
is struggling out there at the moment.
各位 帮我换掉软胎 我越来越慢了
Guys, get me off these softs. I'm going backwards.
收到 20圈 进站...
Copy that. Lap 20. Box, box.
新人约书亚·皮尔斯的成败在此一举
Stakes couldn't be higher for rookie Joshua Pearce.
他现在的排名很不乐观
This is not where you want to be,
是最后一名
in last place.
卡住了 换备用的
I'm jammed. Back up!
碾过了什么东西?
Hit something. What was that?
停站用了七秒
Oh, a seven-second pit stop.
APX GP车队肯定不满意
APX GP won't be happy with that.
比标准用时多了一倍
That's double the time it should've taken.
后轮撑不住了 我要进站
Lost the rears. Box, box.
收到 B计划 进站...
Copy. Go to plan B. Box, box.
桑尼·海耶斯进站
And here comes Sonny Hayes
来换新胎
for a fresh set of tires.
他应该会希望新胎
He'll be hoping these
能帮他保住目前的第15位
will help him hold on to his current position of P15.
前千斤顶...
Front jacks! Front jacks!
前千斤顶出故障了
The front jack has not worked properly.
逗我呢
You're kidding me.
APX GP车队维修区
This is causing absolute pandemonium
乱成一团
in the APX GP pit lane.
这支车队简直状况百出
Whatever could go wrong is going wrong for this team.
海耶斯驶出维修区
And coming out of the pit,
正好卡在队友前面
Hayes just ahead of his teammate,
皮尔斯和海耶斯
as Pearce and Hayes
要在银石赛道一决高下
go battling it out here at Silverstone.
我来了 老头
Coming for you, old man.
我找到节奏了 哥们 叫他给我让车
Got the pace, man. Tell him to let me pass.
好 收到 保住位置待命 凯特
Yeah. Copy. Hold position. Stand by. Kate.
约书亚更快 桑尼的轮胎还是凉的
Josh is faster. Sonny's on cold tires.
好了 桑尼 别闹 让他过去
Yeah, okay, Sonny, no fighting. Let him through.
桑尼 别闹别扭
Sonny, no fighting.
谁闹别扭了?我在比赛
Who's fighting? I'm racing.
桑尼在内线
Sonny on the inside,
约书亚在外线
Pearce on the outside.
海耶斯想把他逼到
Hayes trying to make him eat concrete
维修区那边的混凝土墙上
up against the old pit wall there.
约书亚 你只能自己争取位置了
Joshua, you're gonna have to fight for position.
你在跟桑尼比赛
You are racing Sonny.
收到
A-ffirm.
他们毫不留情
They're giving absolutely no quarter.
队友一点便宜都占不到
No benefit to their teammate at all.
他们你追我赶
They're pushing
好像在争夺大奖赛冠军
as if they're trying to win a Grand Prix.
但别忘了
But this is the battle
这是最后一名之战啊
for last place, remember?
战况真是激烈啊
And what a brawl it is.
来吧 小子 放马过来
Let's go, kid. Bring it.
这人怎么回事?让我超过去
What is this guy doing? Let me through.
最后一个弯
Round the final corner.
只差毫厘
It's close!
撞上了
They make contact.
APX GP车队的两辆赛车全部冲上了沙石区
Both APX GP cars into the gravel,
皮尔斯撞上了护墙
and Pearce hits the barrier.
-不是吧  -不
-Ah, no!  -No!
太疯狂了
This is mad.
赛车运动中的大忌
The cardinal sin of motor racing.
双退
A double DNF.
本以为黑金车队的情况
Just when it couldn't get.
已经糟糕透顶了
any worse for the black and gold.
这局面太惨了 哥们
That's a tough one, man.
我们没法过弯
We can't corner.
车子一路颠得跟搭地铁似的
We're bouncing around the place like we're on the bloody Tube,
现在还觉得把换胎枪落在维修区里也没问题
and now we think it's cool to leave wheel guns in the pit box.
到底是谁的锅?
Who even was that?
-是我  -难怪
-That was me.  -Of course.
老头
Old man.
你聋了吗?刚才怎么回事?
You losing your hearing? What was that?
你想在这里把话说开?
You wanna do this here?
是啊 我就想当着全车队的面跟你说
Yeah, I'd love to do this here in front of the team, right.
反正你也是车队的一员
The one that you're apparently a part of.
好 你犯错了 所以撞车了
Okay. You made a mistake. It happens.
我犯错了 这位真敢说 爱了
I made a mistake. I love this guy, man.
-别往心里去 乔蒂  -你在听我说话吗?
-Don't worry about it, Jodie.  -Are you even listening to me?
-并没有  -别
-Not really.  -No!
住手
Stop.
约书亚是对的
Joshua is right.
命令就是命令
An order is an order.
需要我提醒吗?你要听我的指挥
May I remind you that you report to me?
好
Cool.
但是别想让我让车
Just don't ask me to give up position.
抱歉...各位
Sorry. Sorry, guys.
站住
Hold up.
你很拽地闯进来 像个自以为是的混蛋
You swan into our garage like some entitled prick.
-"拽"?  -说我们是废物
-"Swan"?  -Calling us piss-poor...
-什么叫"拽"?  -然后把车开成这样?
-What's "swan"?  -...and then you drive like that. Huh?
你说我"拽" 什么意思?
You said I "swan." What's that mean?
就是你 你是个混蛋 像个混蛋一样闯进队里 拽得不行
You. You're an arsehole. You come in like an arsehole. You swan.
所以 拽就是混蛋的意思?
So swans are assholes?
如果你认为我会心存敬畏 对老前辈俯首称臣
You're making the mistake of thinking that I'm just gonna be some grateful kid
那你就大错特错了
who'll bend a knee to an old-timer.
我好不容易才有今天的地位 兄弟
I climbed a mountain to get here, bro.
F1
Formula 1.
在我老家 这叫参与奖
Back home we call that a participation trophy.
约书亚...
Joshua, Joshua! Josh!
Yeah.
哥们 你笑什么呢?
What the hell are you smiling about, man?
你赢什么了?
Did you win something?
其他20位车手还在赛道上呢
There's 20 other drivers still out on that track
你却在这里给狗屁媒体摆造型
and you're in here posing for that nonsense.
你觉得他们有谁尊重我们吗? 嗯?
Do you think any of them respect us?  Do you?
他们必须学会 谁也别想轻易超过我
They need to learn that no one gets past us without a fight.
谁也别想
No one.
你不喜欢我这样开车? 那就超过我啊 拽小子
You don't like the way I'm driving? Beat me, swan.
比赛很精彩吧?
Hell of a race, huh?
抱歉 我没看到你
Sorry, I didn't see you.
你还在自责?
You still beating yourself up?
是
Yeah.
我懂这种感觉
Yeah, I know that one.
谢谢你刚才的话
Thanks for what you said out there.
但别再替我出头了 好吗?
Just don't do it again, okay?
那样显得我很无能
Makes me look like I need help.
天 你说得对 明白了
Oh, man. You're right. Got it.
嘿 不管怎样 别对自己太苛刻
Hey, for what it's worth, don't be shitty to yourself.
有的是人对你苛刻
There's plenty of people out there that'll do that for you.
是啊
Yeah.
"抱歉 鲁本 我一下子报废掉你的两台宝贝赛车
"I'm sorry, Ruben, for demolishing not one but both of your lovely cars.
重新回到你的人生 结果害你生不如死"
For coming back into your life only to destroy it."
你在为摩纳哥站复仇?
Is this your revenge for Monaco?
是的 我苦等了30年
Yeah, I waited 30 years
就为了在全球电视观众面前自取其辱
and came all this way to humiliate myself on global television.
有意思 你以为我拉你入队 是为了逼另一位车手退出吗?
Funny. You think I brought you in to make my other driver quit?
听着 他很自负 很傲慢 他要学的东西还多着呢
Listen, he's cocky. He's arrogant. He's got a lot to learn.
你也曾自负 傲慢 也曾有很多东西要学
You were cocky, you were arrogant and you had a lot to learn.
我不是来带新人学开车的 我是来赛车的
I'm not here to hold anyone's hand. I'm here to race.
不 桑尼 你是来给我上强度的
No, you're not, Sonny. You're here to give me a heart attack.
董事会对我疯狂施压
The board is up my ass
我得作出决定 是继续这场闹剧
and I have to decide whether to continue this fiasco
还是立刻喊停
or pull the plug now.
离赛季结束还有时间呢
You have till the end of the season.
到了那时候 APX GP车队会一文不值
By which time APX will be worth less than my shoes!
桑尼!
Sonny! God...
跟我说说凯特
Tell me about Kate.
我是说车 我想跟她聊聊车的事情
The car. I wanna talk to her about the car.
她是世界首位担任F1车队技术总监的女性
She's the world's first female tech director of an F1 team.
这需要勇气
I mean, that takes balls.
哇偶? 你想用这个搭讪?
Wow. Is that your line?
她一眼就能看透
She'll see right through it.
不是搭讪用的
Not a line.
-抱歉...  -她结婚了?
-Oh, I'm sorry. Sorry.  -Is she married?
够了 到匈牙利站前给我一直待在冰水里
Okay, stay there in that tub of ice until Budapest.
你不许出来
You don't move.
嘿 鲁本
Hey, Ruben...
靠这辆车是上不了领奖台的
We can't get there with this car.
激光开启
嘿...
Hey. Hey.
抱歉 嗨...
Yeah, sorry. Hi, hi, hi.
你在忙什么呢?
What you working on?
我正在开发一个新前翼
I'm working on a new front wing concept.
争取能提升大约0.1秒的圈速
Trying to pick us up a tenth or so.
厉害 能模拟弯道吗?
Cool. And you can replicate turns?
横向气流呢?
Lateral airflow?
不能 只有直线阻力
No, just straight line drag.
但是可以以此为基础来计算
But, I mean, we can calculate it from there.
好 那跟在一辆车后面遇到的乱流呢?
Okay, what about turbulent air from the car we're following?
不能 但...
No, not exactly, but...
赛道状况、路面质量、天气、气温?
Track conditions, surface quality, weather, ambient temps?
抱歉 你有什么事要谈吗?
I'm sorry, is there something that you wanted to discuss?
凯特 你知道我在想什么
Kate, you read my mind.
所以 一个人要怎样才能成为首位F1车队的女性技术总监呢?
So how does one get to be the first female technical director of an F1 team?
一定需要...
Must take...
奉献精神 并付出大量辛勤的汗水
dedication and lots of hard work.
这就是你急着要问的事?
That's your urgent question?
很多人觉得我不该出现在这里
Plenty of people think I don't belong here
如果你也在暗示那个意思
and I'm happy to add you to the list
那我很乐意把你归入那类人
if you're implying what I... I think you're implying.
我向来不做暗示
As a rule I don't imply stuff.
所以你有话直说?
So you like straight talk?
直言不讳 不加修饰
Straight as an arrow. No sugar.
所有人都觉得鲁本疯了
Everyone thinks Ruben's lost it.
他在握紧最后的救命稻草
That he is clutching at straws.
说"也许他打赌输了 或者撞死了你的狗"
They're saying maybe he lost a bet. Ran over your dog.
他们说桑尼·海耶斯还没过气呢
They're saying Sonny Hayes isn't a has-been.
他是根本就没火过
He's a never-was.
好吧 我说喜欢直言不讳 我指的是我自己说
Yeah, when I said I like straight talk I meant me.
从其他人那里 我更喜欢听赞美、吹捧、英雄崇拜
From others, I mostly prefer praise, flattery, hero worship,
有时胡说八道也行
at times, straight-up bullshit.
这是鲁本的职责吧?
Is that what Ruben's for?
我很喜欢鲁本 他是最可靠、最坚定的...
Ruben. I love the guy. Most solid, steadfast...
他说 你问我是不是结婚了
Said you asked if I was married.
不忠、卑鄙、阴险、怨毒 徒有其表的男人
Disloyal, mean, twisted, bitter, husk of a man.
他还跟我说 你的前妻、前女友数量可是相当可观呢
Yeah. And he also told me about a big string of ex-wives and girlfriends.
他说 要像躲瘟疫一样躲着你
He said to avoid you like the plague.
好吧 容我解释
Okay, let me explain this.
当你以300多公里的时速 冲进艾尔罗格弯
When you're going 200 miles per hour into Eau Rouge,
知道有谁在背后支持你很重要
it's good to know who's got your back.
还有 正式声明 我赛车这些年
And for the record, in all my years of racing,
从来没勾搭过车队的技术总监
I have never ever hit on the team technical director.
听你说完 我还真是如释重负了呢
Well, now that's a huge weight off my mind.
所以你到底急着想问什么?
So what's this urgent question?
Okay.
红牛、法拉利、梅奔、阿斯顿马丁就连迈凯伦
Red Bull, Ferrari, Mercedes, Aston, now McLaren
全都在直道超越过我们
all have us beat on straight line speed.
我们的超车机会在弯中
Our shot is battling in the turns.
我需要一个办法 能让我在乱流中不受影响
I need a way to chase through the dirty air.
你想让我重新设计 好让你跟车更近?
You want me to redesign so you can follow closer?
我们必须打造"战车"
We need to build our car for combat.
这叫我怎么保障车辆安全?
How am I supposed to make that safe?
谁说要安全了?
Who said anything about safe?
这就是你要问的?
That's your question?
是的
Yeah.
这就是直言不讳
And here's the straight talk.
很急
It's urgent.
我打赌 你照镜子的时候
You know, I bet when you look in the mirror,
会看到一位粗犷豪放 老派作风 直来直去的牛仔
you see this rough-and-tumble, old school, no bullshit cowboy.
不听命令 我行我素 是吧?
Doesn't take orders. Goes his own way. Huh?
一只独狼
A lone wolf.
那我给你上一课
Well, I have news for you.
F1是团队运动 向来如此
Formula 1 is a team sport. It always was.
也许这就是你失败的原因?
And maybe that's why you failed at it.
这里只有一个问题 "桑尼·海耶斯为什么重返F1赛场?"
The only question here is, why did Sonny Hayes come back to F1?
这个问题才是急上加急
Now that question is extremely fucking urgent.
等你能完赛后 我再听你要求
I'll start listening to you when you finish a race.
F1  回放
在西班牙大奖赛上
At the Spanish Grand Prix
1993 西班牙大奖赛 回顾
美国新人桑尼·海耶斯...
the American rookie Sonny Hayes
刚刚签了新的合同
had just signed a new contract,
他的未来一片光明
and his future looked very bright.
他因激进的驾驶风格
He'd earned a reputation
而声名在外
for his aggressive driving style.
有些人认为这种风格颇为鲁莽
Seen by some as reckless,
但它确实为他带来了不小的回报
it nevertheless served him well
西班牙 赫雷斯赛道
他在这个赛季
as he climbed up the order
排名不断攀升
over the course of the season,
不懈地追求
relentlessly pursuing
他的第一个F1冠军
his first F1 victory.
海耶斯在开局几圈表现出色
Hayes was running well in the opening laps,
紧追领跑的埃尔顿·塞纳
chasing down race leader, Ayrton Senna.
然而 当海耶斯在高速右弯
However when Hayes made a risky move
冒险从外线
and attacked Senna
超越塞纳时
on the outside of a high-speed right-hand turn,
骇人的一幕瞬间上演
a frightening scene unfolded as quick as a flash.
天啊 我看到他从赛道右侧冲出去了
My goodness! I just saw him plunge off to the right.
可以看到右侧全是赛车残骸
And you can see the debris on the right.
我不知道到底发生了什么
What on earth happened there, I don't know.
是的 看起来确实非常严重
Yes, this looks very severe indeed.
不得不说 看起来他..
I must say it looks like he is...
1993 西班牙大奖赛 回顾
真的需要帮助
he really needs help.
目前还没有人去救他
There is nobody coming to him at the moment.
比赛已经终止
The race has been stopped.
赛会出示了红旗
The red flag is out.
看起来有点...
This looks a little bit like a...
匈牙利大奖赛
亨格罗宁赛道
我们的模型预测 所有车队都会采用一停策略
Our models predict all teams are gonna be targeting a one-stop race.
A计划是在第27到33圈之间 从中性胎换到硬胎
Plan A is to switch from mediums to hards, between lap 27 and 33.
B计划是中、硬、中 一停在16到21圈之间 二停在45到51圈
Plan B will be medium-hard-medium, first window 16 to 21, second, 45 to 51.
C计划用软胎 这个方案不合理
Plan C for softs doesn't make sense.
在这个温度下 软胎磨损会过于严重
At this temp, the tire deg will be too high.
还有要补充的吗?
Nothing else?
-有  -约书亚 请讲
-Yep.  -Yeah, Joshua?
我们可以好好赛车吗?
So, we've just got to drive our race, all right?
别逞英雄
Let's not try and be heroes.
顺利通过前几个弯
Just make it through those first turns clean.
我们从后排起步 不可能在第一圈就赢
Can't win at lap one, starting at the back,
所以只能希望后期能走运 对吗?
so we just gotta hope for some lucky breaks later on, all right?
-对  -好
-Yeah.  -Yeah.
要自己创造突破
Create your own breaks.
喂 有在听吗?我刚说过
Hello, hi? I just said that.
"希望"不是战术
Hope is not a strategy.
教授 还有要补充的吗?
Anything else, Professor?
开快点?
Drive fast?
五盏红灯熄灭 比赛开始
It's lights out, and away we go.
汉密尔顿起步不错
Great start from Hamilton,
维斯塔潘在跟他抢位置
Verstappen battling with him.
皮亚斯特里、周冠宇、勒克莱尔
Piastri, Zhou and Leclerc...
还有两位APX GP车队车手
and here come the two APX GPs.
但嘉斯利封锁了线路
But Gasly shuts the door,
他们无处可去
leaving them with nowhere to go.
在一号弯
Into turn one
三辆赛车冲出赛道
and there's three cars gone off.
嘉斯利、奥康
Gasly, Ocon,
和小红牛车队的角田
and the AlphaTauri, Tsunoda.
压到碎片了 检查我的轮胎
Hit debris. Check my tires.
OK 右后胎爆了 这圈进站
Yeah, you've got a puncture. Right rear. Box. Box this lap.
该死 才第一个弯 这场比赛毁了
First goddamn turn. A ruined race.
该死...
Oh, shit, shit, shit. Ah, shit.
他来了 上
He's coming in! Let's go.
用C计划吧
Let's go Plan C.
不 C计划是软胎 这种气温 根本坚持不了十圈 不行
No, Plan C is for soft tires. They won't last ten laps in this heat. No.
不行 桑尼 用A计划
That's a negative, Sonny. Plan A.
A计划之所以叫A计划 因为是为万事顺利的情况准备的
Plan A is called Plan A 'cause it's when everything is going right.
你看现在顺利吗?
You see anything going right?
C计划 用软胎
Plan C. Softs.
他说的不算 告诉他用A计划 这个混蛋
It's not his call. Tell him A, as in "asshole."
好 快点 搬出来 硬胎
Okay, let's go! Turn 'em out! Hard tires.
软胎 该死的
Softs, goddamn it.
-车怎么了?  -他不开
-What's wrong with the car?  -The guy sitting in it.
你疯了吗?我们必须用硬胎 所有车手都用一停策略
Are you insane? We need hard tires. Everybody here is at a one-stop race.
我们跟着他们的策略就输定了
We do what everybody does, we lose.
-叫他开车  -怎么叫?
-Make him go!  -How?
你认为我不懂轮胎?我当过机械师
You think I don't know my tires? I was a mechanic.
凭这双手拿过五次冠军
Five championship titles with my bare freaking hands!
给他换软胎
Give him his tires.
-好 快  -快...换胎...
-Okay, let's go. -Go, go, go, change!
快...快换 立刻
Let's go, let's go! Change quick, now!
做好准备
Be ready.
准备什么?
Ready for what?
第10圈
-JP在什么位置?  -目前在第14位
-Where's JP sitting?  -Currently running P14.
好 来了
All right, here we go now.
海耶斯行动了!
Hayes makes his move!
猛追马格努森
Chasing Kevin Magnussen,
这是一次晚刹车进攻
it's a late lunge!
他的前翼受损了
And he's damaged his front wing.
任何一个车手都知道 马格努森
Any driver knows Magnussen
不可能让这种拙劣的招数得逞
will shut the door on a clumsy move like that.
真该死
Aw, dagnabbit.
C计划就是"混乱"
Plan C for "chaos."
此举导致安全车上场
So that will bring out a safety car
这必然会让比赛局势大洗牌
which always shakes up a race.
迫使领先的车手减速
Slows down the leaders,
让其他车手挤在一起
leaves the field bunched up together,
让各车队有机会快速进入维修区
and gives teams the chance for a quick pit stop,
只用平常耗时的一半
which only costs half the usual time.
安全车 我们要进站吗?
Safety car. We're boxing, right?
待命 凯特
Standby. Kate,
我们要不要利用安全车这个窗口?
shouldn't we take advantage while the safety car window is open?
还太早 如果不进站 我们的排位能上升
It's early. We gain track position if we stay out.
待在赛道上...我们要你推进 加速...约书亚
Stay out, stay out. Want you out. Push, push, Joshua.
中游车阵暂时整体上移
So, the midfield moves up for the moment,
约书亚·皮尔斯升至第12位
including Joshua Pearce to P12.
这人最好别给我的比赛捣乱
This guy better not be messing up my race.
JP现在排第几?
Where's JP now?
目前在第12位
Currently running P12.
好 C计划 做好准备
Okay. Plan C. Be ready.
他要故技重施
He's gonna do it again.
第14圈
后排起步的海耶斯现在已经被套了一圈
Back marker Hayes is now down a lap.
他必须让博塔斯超过去
He has to let Bottas pass,
否则将面临五秒的罚时
or face a five-second penalty.
海耶斯在给博塔斯制造麻烦
Hayes is making it very difficult for Bottas.
在当前规则下 他必须
Under the rules, he has to let him through
在通过三面蓝旗前让博塔斯过去
before passing three blue flags,
否则将会被判罚
or risk a penalty.
嘿 我就是说啊 也许该换你去开
Hey, I'm just putting it out there, but maybe you should drive.
桑尼 你已经通过蓝旗了 让博塔斯超过去
Sonny, you've gotten the blue flag. Let Bottas through.
来吧 再近一点
Come on, now. Little closer.
桑尼 听见了吗?
Sonny, do you copy?
听见了 我让他过去
I hear ya. Lettin' him through.
哎呀 是我不好
Whoops, my bad.
他的前翼又坏了
And that's his front wing again!
这下安全车又要上场了
That's gonna bring out another safety car.
一个前翼就要二十多万英镑
Given that each wing costs more than £200,000,
我觉得车队可能希望
I think the team might want
桑尼自己掏点钱了
Sonny to start chipping in there.
各位 又一次免费维修的机会 是不是要进站啊?
Guys, it's another free stop. Please tell me we're boxing.
我们在计算
We're checking.
-让他继续开  -继续比赛...你继续开
-Keep him out.  -Stay out. Stay out. You are staying out.
有更多车手进站换胎
More drivers come in to take fresh tires,
但约书亚·皮尔斯依然留在赛道
but still, Joshua Pearce remains on track.
他来到了第11位
He's moved up to P11.
看是谁回来了
Look who's back.
我知道...准备好
I know, I know. Be ready.
他要干吗?
What is he doing?
我觉得他想为车队拿到一分
I think he's trying to score us a point.
叫JP省着点用轮胎
Tell JP to save his tires.
约书亚 保护轮胎 明白吗?
Joshua, just take care of your tires, okay?
努力撑久一点
You have to make them last.
撑久一点? 真假? 我尽力
Last? No shit. I will be.
第66圈
还有四圈 这场比赛停停走走
With four laps to go in this stop-and-go race,
全拜桑尼·海耶斯所赐
thanks to Sonny Hayes,
收益最多的车手是他的队友
the driver helped most is his teammate,
现在排在第十位
now in tenth
领先斯托尔12秒
with a 12-second gap ahead of Stroll.
叫JP保持这个差距
Tell JP to maintain that gap.
继续加速
Keep pushing.
我的轮胎不行了 兄弟 你在等什么?
My tires are gone, man. What are you waiting for?
收到 我们必须喊他进站了
Copy that. We have to call it.
他现在每圈落后一秒
He's losing over a second every lap.
等等
Stand by.
进入二号弯
Into turn two.
海耶斯对威廉姆斯发起进攻
Hayes battles with the Williams
来到了外线
and pushes it wide.
认真的吗? 我们到底在等什么?
Seriously, what are we waiting for?
桑尼跑出赛道了
Sonny's off the track.
跑偏太多了
He's gone too far over.
造成了严重的破坏
And that's gonna cause damage.
C计划
Plan C.
哎呀 抱歉了 各位
Oopsie. Sorry, guys.
APX GP车队的车手第三次
That's the third safety car
引发了安全车出动
involving the APX GP driver,
匈牙利大奖赛变成了大塞车
bringing the Hungarian Grand Prix to an absolute crawl.
三秒内完成换胎 他就能保住第十名
A sub three-second stop, and he'll keep P10.
进站 约书亚 进站...
Box, Joshua. Box, box, box.
收到 来了
Copy. Coming in.
你说什么?
What did you say?
约书亚·皮尔斯终于进维修区了
Joshua Pearce finally gets to pit.
快速出站的话
And with a quick stop here,
他也许能保住前十
he could stay in the top ten.
太关键了
This is critical.
皮尔斯必须在维修区出口线处领先斯托尔
Pearce must beat Stroll to the pit exit line
才能保住第十名的位置
to maintain tenth place.
他做到了
And he's done it!
随着黄旗挥出
With yellow flags out,
所有赛车必须维持原位 禁止超车
all the cars are forced to hold track position,
Let's go!
也就是说 多亏了桑尼·海耶斯
meaning that thanks to Sonny Hayes...
Yeah!
Vegas!  WOW!
Hey, yeah. Fuck you.
Yeah!
Yes, baby.
你真是疯子 兄弟
You're crazy, bro.
才第十名 你笑什么呢?
It's just tenth. What are you smiling about?
而在领奖台之外
And behind our podium placings,
汉密尔顿和皮亚斯特里 分列四五 组成了前五名
Hamilton and Piastri complete the top five,
约书亚·皮尔斯排在第十
and Joshua Pearce in tenth...
为APX GP车队...
...scoring Expensify APX GP
赢得了队史第一分
...their first ever point!
看到我了吗?不可思议吧?
Did you see me? Crazy, right?
说话算话 我完成比赛了  -是啊 最后一名
A deal's a deal. I finished.  -Yeah, in last place.
你说出来就很动听
Sounds great when you say it.
我知道你等下要去见赛事干事
I know you have to go and see the stewards later,
你觉得他们会怎么看你今天的比赛?
what do you think they're gonna make of your race today?
不得不说 这回你们判断得很准
Well, I have to admit, you guys got this one right.
-我...谢谢...  -好样的
-I'm, like... Thank you. Thank you.  -Good job. Yeah.
我还有些生疏 还在熟悉这辆车
I'm still a bit rusty and, you know, finding my way with this car,
但我有信心 我们能成功
but I'm confident we'll get there.
在银石赛道扮猪吃老虎 在匈牙利上演撞车大赛
A rope-a-dope at Silverstone, a demolition derby here in Hungary...
赌场都把你封杀了
You've been banned from casinos.
你是想被F1封杀吗? 拖整个车队下水?
Are you trying to get banned from F1? Take the whole team down with you?
我跟你讲 唐 我们打个赌如何?
Tell you what, Don, what do you say we make a bet?
你出10英镑 我出一万
Your £10 against my 10 grand.
我在蒙扎拿到积分 我赢你10英镑 若做不到 你赢我一万
We place at Monza, I win your 10. We don't, you win mine.
来啊 敢说不敢赌吗?
Let's do this, man. Put your money where your mouth is.
管它呢 我接受
What the hell? I'll take that.
-谢谢  -多谢
-Thank you.  -Thank you so much.
嘿 我不再接受采访了
Hey. No more press.
不是 桑尼 别和媒体过不去
No, Sonny, you don't wanna make the media your enemy.
你会被罚款的
And you'll be fined.
从我工资里扣好了
Take it out of my paycheck.
你的工资都不够扣的
We don't pay you enough.
Mclaren MP4/5B
你还真别说
You know, I have to say.
我还挺喜欢这样的
I kinda like it.
很有朋克摇滚风
It's very sort of punk rock for the brand.
我们再来一次
Let's run it again.
他在里面多久了?
How long's he been in there?
一整天了 在试不同的胎压、行驶高度
All day. Playing with different tire pressures, ride heights.
他的成绩呢?
What were his times?
提高了半秒
He found half a second.
给我跟他一样的设置
Give me the same setup as him.
一定很晚了 我看东西都重影了
It must be late. I'm seeing double.
说话算话 我在把它打造成战车
A deal's a deal. I'm building her for combat.
在荷兰大奖赛上
At the Dutch Grand Prix,
你将以322公里的时速冲入Tarzanbocht(1号弯)
you'll be entering the Tarzan Corner at 322 kilometers per hour.
好 现在反悔是不是太晚了?
Yeah. Too late to change my mind?
是的
Yeah.
回答你的问题吧
To answer your question,
我当时在洛克希德 从事航空航天工作 鲁本找到我...
I was in aerospace at Lockheed when Ruben came in and...
他喜欢我的工作和态度
He liked my work, liked my attitude,
说赛车会为了十分之一秒的差异 殊死拼搏 非常刺激 把我说服了
and he sold me on the thrill of fighting to the death for a tenth of a second.
周游世界 观众的欢呼
Traveling the world, the roar of a crowd...
于是我跟老公商量了一下
So, I ran the idea past my husband.
他就迅速变成前夫了
Who swiftly became my ex-husband.
晚安
Good night.
鲁本·塞万提斯
你知道现在几点了吗?
Do you know what time it is?
好吧
All right.
跟我说说那小子
Tell me about the kid.
意大利大奖赛
蒙扎赛道
好 再来一句我爸的格言
Okay, here's another one my dad would say.
"慢即是稳 稳即是快"
"Slow is smooth, smooth is fast."
无论如何 再来一圈?
For what it's worth. One more time around?
就一圈? 拜托 就这样?
Just one? Come on. Is that all?
我要是跟不上你的速度 那我可丢人了 90年代人
I'd never live with myself, if I can't keep up with you, Mr. 1990s.
冲啊
Let's go!
今天我们请到了卡什帕斯·莫林克斯基
Joining us today, we have Kaspar Smolinski,
扎克·布朗和弗雷德·瓦塞尔
Zak Brown and Fred Vasseur.
卡什帕 从你开始吧 上次你们车队
Now, Kaspar, can we start with you, after what was a fantastic result
-在匈牙利站的成绩喜人  -谢谢
-for the team in Hungary last time out...  -Thank you.
但桑尼让你险些违规受罚
...but Sonny has got you skirting the line of penalties and violations.
这是你唯一的战术吗?
Is this your only strategy,
你们车队工厂里还有备用零件吗?
and have you got any spare parts left in the factory?
我们比赛的方式和其他车队一样
We compete like everybody else.
比赛模式不断变化
Race models change.
我们必须去适应 对吧?
We must adapt, huh?
扎克 能说说你的想法吗?
Well, Zak, can we bring you in on this?
因为你之前和海耶斯在赛道上较量过 你知道他总是游走在规则的灰色地带
Because you've faced Hayes before, you know the gray areas in which he works.
当然 首先 他现在两鬓"灰"白  人也更加老奸巨猾了
Certainly do. First of all, he's a lot grayer now.
我们盯着他呢 用后视镜
And we keep tabs on him, you know, back there behind us.
弗雷德 法拉利车队有顾虑吗?
And Fred, any concerns from Ferrari?
法拉利对APX有什么看法?
What does Ferrari think of APX?
我们不看
We don't.
桑尼 你是最强的
Sonny! You're the best!
昨天排位赛跑得不错 让我们成功挤进了最激烈的竞争圈
A better qualifying yesterday gets us in the thick of things.
第10位、第15位
P10, P15.
所以我们要采用两停策略
So we're gonna go for a two stop.
中胎、硬胎、中胎 这是A计划 如果是B计划 最后一段用硬胎
Medium-hard-medium, that's plan A. Final stint, we go hards for plan B.
说到这里 你对赛道有顾虑吗?
So, on this, do you have any track concerns?
别看我 看他
Don't look at me. Look at him.
赛道对JP有利
It's good for JP.
让我用硬胎起步
Start me on hards.
不行 赛道已经凉了 你的抓地力会很小
Nah, the track's cooled down. You won't have any grip.
是的
That's right.
三周了 大家都在说我多么鲁莽
For three weeks, all the talk's been how reckless I am.
所有人都在想会不会被我逼出赛道
Everyone's wondering if I'm gonna drive 'em off track,
也就是说 没人会防他
which means no one's gonna be watching out for him.
今天 要靠你来为车队赢下比赛
Today, you win us this race.
第20圈
比赛已经进行到第20圈
Twenty laps down here at Monza,
车手们已经散开
and the pack have been split.
领先集团由维斯塔潘带头
The leaders are pulling away
已经开始甩开其他车手
led by Max Verstappen,
约书亚·皮尔斯回到了第十位
with Joshua Pearce back in P10.
同时
Meanwhile
桑尼·海耶斯阻挡着其他车手
Sonny Hayes is holding up the rest of the pack,
排成一列DRS火车
stuck behind him in a DRS train.
皮尔斯看起来很有希望
Pearce looks to be in a great position
冲进前十名完赛
to finish in the top ten,
甚至可能登上领奖台呢
and maybe even a run to the podium.
但比赛还远没有结束
But there's still a long way to go in this race,
天气预报有雨
and with rain potentially forecast,
一切皆有可能
anything can happen.
轮胎不行了 我要进站
Tires are gone. Coming in.
好 收到 进站
Yeah, copy. Box. Box.
APX GP车队在为海耶斯
APX GP is prepping
准备一套新胎
a fresh set of tires for Hayes.
这会带动其他车队
That's gonna bring in all the other teams
跟随进站以避免被undercut
to avoid the undercut.
我改主意了
Changed my mind.
但他没进
But, no! He's staying out,
而是继续比赛
with the cars behind him all scrambling
而他身后的赛车纷纷进站换上新胎
to get on fresh tires
显然 他觉得自己并不需要
that apparently he doesn't think he needs anymore.
我们要不要彻底跟他唱反调?
Should we just do the opposite of what he tells us to do?
准备好 等我轮胎报废
Stand by till I lose my tires.
-我以为他的轮胎已经报废了  -我认为他说的是字面意思
-I thought he had lost his tires.  -I think he means literally.
爆胎了 左后轮 我进站了
Puncture, left rear. Coming in.
海耶斯的轮胎爆掉了
And there goes Hayes's tires.
现场一团糟 赛道上碎石遍布
That's quite a mess, gravel on the track.
这样一来 赛会将启动虚拟安全车
That will bring out the virtual safety car
来清理赛道
for a quick sweep.
这意味着差距将会被中和
So the race gets neutralized.
所有赛车将降速至正常速度的40%
Everyone slows down to 40% of their racing speed,
所有的比赛策略也将被彻底重置
and all the race strategies will get a reset.
所以此时最适合进维修区
And that is why this is the perfect time to take a pit stop.
进维修区的同时
While you're in the pit lane,
因为对手车速大大受限
your opponents are restricted to a much slower pace
这样重新回到赛道时
and you're not going to
排位不会掉太多
lose as much track position when you rejoin.
-我猜我要继续比赛 对吗?  -收到 约书亚 继续比赛...
-I take it I'm staying out, right?  -Copy. Joshua, stay out. Stay out.
-我们希望你提升排名  -收到
-We want you out to gain track position.  -Copy.
提升即下降 下降即提升
Up is down, down is up.
桑尼·海耶斯离开维修区的时候犹豫了一下
Sonny Hayes hesitated before he left his pit box,
出来后刚好挡在维斯塔潘前面
and he's come out just in front of Max Verstappen.
很皮啊
That was naughty.
海耶斯在维修区略微减速
Hayes has slowed a bit in the pit lane,
这将耗费红牛和两辆法拉利的宝贵时间
which will cost the Red Bull and the two Ferraris precious time.
约书亚 加速...
Push, Joshua. Push.
你现在排在第四位...
You are now P4. P4.
是谁后来居上?
Who's coming up from behind?
他来了 约书亚·皮尔斯
Here he is, Joshua Pearce.
-看吧 冲啊  -太好了
-Let's see! Let's go!  -Yes!
目前这一切都在朝着
This is all playing into his hands...
对他有利的方向发展
at the moment.
可能会变成梦幻结局 ...
Could be a dream afternoon.
但海耶斯能否再多阻挡维斯塔潘一阵?
But can Hayes hold Verstappen for a little bit longer?
维斯塔潘试图在一号弯超车
Verstappen tries into turn one,
未能如愿
nothing doing there.
出弯占优 两人一起冲进大看台(3号弯)
Gets the better exit.Through the Curva Grande we go.
该死 他真厉害
Damn, he's good.
维斯塔潘想超车
Verstappen's trying to get past.
桑尼·海耶斯仔细观察着后视镜
Sonny Hayes looking carefully in his mirrors.
他不得不让维斯塔潘过去了
He must let Max Verstappen through.
对 我活该
Yeah, I deserved that.
而维斯塔潘表示了不满
And Max shows his disapproval,
这不怪他
and I don't blame him,
两人来到了第二组连续弯
as they head down towards the second chicane.
排在第四位的约书亚·皮尔斯来了
And through goes Joshua Pearce in P4,
已经逼近领先集团
now much closer to the front of the pack.
第46圈
还有七圈
Just seven laps to go,
降雨如期而至
and here comes the rain.
让我们看看谁会选择稳妥地换上半雨胎
Let's see who plays it safe with a switch to the intermediate tire,
又有谁会冒险坚持用干胎继续比赛
and who might gamble to stay out on slicks.
比赛开始困难了 各位 有什么计划吗?
It's getting tricky out here, guys. What's the plan?
你现在排第四位 我们认为 第二和第三要换半雨胎 以求安全
You're running P4. We think P2 and P3 are switching to inters for safety,
看起来第一要继续比赛
and it looks like P1 is staying out.
-你有什么打算?  -桑尼会怎么做?
-What do you wanna do?  -What's Sonny gonna do?
大胆猜猜吧
Take a wild guess.
-我继续比赛  -收到
-I'm staying out.  -Copy that.
两辆法拉利进站换半雨胎
And the two Ferraris come in for intermediate tires.
看看还有谁要打安全牌
Let's see who else decides to play it safe.
随着拉塞尔进站
And as George Russell pits,
约书亚·皮尔斯来到了第二位
Joshua Pearce moves into P2.
桑尼 约书亚用干胎继续比赛 如果他能顶住 并找到一条干线
Sonny, Joshua is staying out on slicks. If he can hold on and find a dry line,
他将以第二名完赛
he's gonna finish second.
第二名不够
Second's not enough.
该死
Damn it.
好 我来换半雨胎了
Okay, coming in for inters.
-半雨胎...  -快 他要进站了
-Inters, inters.  -Let's go! He's coming in!
-他们在我后面多远处?  -30秒
-How far behind me are they?  -Thirty seconds.
天啊 他打算干掉维斯塔潘
Oh, my God. He's gonna take out Verstappen.
他们来到主直道时告诉我
Let me know when they hit the main straight.
别信他 他们两辆车都会罚 会取消比赛成绩
Don't trust him! They penalize both cars. They will take the win away.
相信我好吗?
Just trust me, will ya?
我在加速 但追不上他
I'm pushing but I can't catch him.
领先车手们接近主直道了
As the race leaders approach the main straight,
桑尼·海耶斯再次因为车队策略和指挥僵持不下
Sonny Hayes is in another standoff over team strategy.
-来了  -不
1Now.  1No!
海耶斯终于返回了赛道
Finally, Hayes back out onto the track,
刚好来到维斯塔潘前面
and just in front of Verstappen.
赛会出示了蓝旗
Now, he'll get a blue flag here
要让维斯塔潘超车
so Verstappen can get past,
但在超车之前
but until then,
这位荷兰车手不得不在海耶斯的乱流中行驶
the Dutch driver is caught up in Hayes's dirty air.
每一个弯中 他都在坚持
With every turn he hangs on,
他把维斯塔潘拖慢了零点几秒
he slows Verstappen a fraction of a second,
给约书亚·皮尔斯创造最后一次赶超的机会
providing Joshua Pearce one last chance to catch up.
我看到他了 还差一点赶上
I can see him. I'm almost there.
叫JP跟着我
Tell JP to follow me.
-收到 约书亚 跟着桑尼吃尾流  -我在他正后方
-Copy. Joshua, Sonny is your tow.  -I'm right behind him.
维斯塔潘已经超到前面去了
Verstappen pulls away then.
但现在 约书亚·皮尔斯已经追到了
But now, onto the rear wing of his teammate's car
队友的尾翼后方
comes Joshua Pearce.
皮尔斯借助海耶斯的尾流
Pearce picks up the slipstream from Hayes,
迅速拉近时间
gaining time,
但在水雾遮挡下几乎盲驾前行
but driving blind in the spray.
加油 跟紧了...
Come on. Stay with me. Stay with me now.
超车...
Pass. Pass.
-超车...  -收到
-Overtake him. Overtake.  -Copy.
他一直在追赶 突然之间
He's been gaining, and boom!
约书亚·皮尔斯飞速超过桑尼·海耶斯
Joshua Pearce slingshots past Sonny Hayes,
第一的位置触手可及了
and now is in striking distance of P1.
告诉JP等到进入一号弯前的直道再超车
Tell JP to wait for the straight into turn one.
耐心点
Be patient.
-一号弯前的直道  -收到
-Straight at turn one.  -Copy.
约书亚 桑尼说等直道 一号弯前的直道
Joshua, Sonny says wait for the straight. The straight into turn one.
我很靠近了
I'm right there.
追上他了
I've got him.
皮尔斯几乎贴在维斯塔潘的变速箱上
Pearce is right on the gearbox of Verstappen,
两人在直道末端时速超过320公里
Mdown the back straight at over 200 miles an hour.
有机会 我要上了
I see an opening. Going for it.
新人在11号弯位发起了进攻
The rookie attacks in 11.
别...
No, no!
皮尔斯和红牛并驾齐驱
Pearce pulls alongside the Red Bull...
Go, go, go!
他的车轮领先了
...he's wheels ahead,
APX GP车队有史以来第一次...
for the first time ever... APX GP...
不好...
Oh, no! No!
老天爷
For God's sake.
伯纳黛特 他怎么样?
Bernadette, how's he doing?
情况稳定
He's stable.
正在休息
He's resting now.
那太好了
Very happy to hear it.
我对事故深表遗憾 显然是...
I'm so sorry for what happened. It was clearly...
桑尼 请来一下
Sonny, over here, please.
我想说 我一直...
I just wanna say I've been..
约书亚说你是个混蛋
Joshua says you're an asshole.
确实是
Yeah, that tracks.
我认为你是个危险的混蛋
I think you're a dangerous asshole.
-皮尔斯女士...  -你们是同一个车队的 对吗?
-Ms. Pearce..  -You're part of the same team, right?
应该彼此关照
Looking out for each other.
但你却让他出险招
Except you had him doing something so dangerous
差点害死他
it almost got him killed.
-好 听我...  -不 你听我说
-Okay, listen...  -No, you listen to me.
他是我的儿子
This is my son.
如果他...再出点什么事 我跟你没完
And if anything... anything else happens to him, I'm coming after you.
你最好祈祷我不会把你也送进医院
And you better pray I don't put you in a bed next to Joshua
长期躺在约书亚旁边
for a very, very long time.
明白吗?
Clear?
明白
Sure.
桑尼...
Sonny, Sonny.
你觉得蒙扎的事故 约书亚会怪你吗?
Do you think Joshua blames you for what happened in Monza?
桑尼 说话啊
Sonny, come on.
显然是你在控制他的比赛
It was clear that you were running his race.
你让他在危险的路况继续用干胎
Look, you kept him out on slick tires, in dangerous conditions,
即使你叫他别超车 事故难道不是必然的吗?
that even if you told him not to pass, wasn't the accident inevitable?
请安静...
If I may. If I may.
约书亚回家了 正在康复
Joshua's back home, recovering.
我们预计他几周后可以归队
We are expecting his return in a few weeks.
在那之前 我们的后备车手
Until that moment, our reserve driver,
卢卡·科尔特斯将会参赛 他就在那里...
Luca Cortez right there, will drive and...
-轮到下一个人上了  1回答问题
-Next man up.  -Answer the question!
APX GP车队经历了混乱的一周
A chaotic week for Expensify APX GP,
风暴的中心又是桑尼·海耶斯
and again, it's Sonny Hayes at the center.
很多人把他队友可怕的事故
Many are blaming him
怪在他头上
for his teammate's horrific accident at Monza.
他那种孤注一掷、充满赌性的赛车风格
His high-stakes, gambling style of racing
让所有车手都如坐针毡
has the whole grid on edge,
但是目前事故责任
and while the controversy continues
仍众说纷纭
over who was to blame,
而医生已经证实
doctors have said
皮尔斯将缺席未来三站比赛
Pearce will miss the next three races,
因为他双手烧伤
due to the burns suffered on his hands
康复之旅才刚刚开始
as he begins his road to recovery.
荷兰大奖赛
赞德福特赛道
今天 我们的赛车升级为"战车"了
Today, we're going with our combat upgrade.
修改后的车身将改善底板下的气流场
The revised shapes will improve the flow field under the floor,
使我们即使在乱流中行驶时 也能最大限度地减少性能损失
allowing us to run in dirty air with minimal loss of performance.
意味着我们必须紧跟在其他赛车后面
Means we have to keep the field close at all times,
至于这周的C计划...
and as for this week's plan C...
他们把我们罚到队尾发车 因为他们不喜欢我们的驾驶方式
They've docked us to the back of the grid 'cause they don't like the way we drive.
行 去他*的
Fine. Fuck 'em.
但是如果我能靠你
'Cause if we can pick up a tenth of a second from you,
你、你、还有我 各提升0.1秒
and from you, and you, and me...
如果在座的每个人都能做出一项关键贡献
If everyone in this room can make one critical contribution,
那就是每圈追一秒
that's a second every lap.
72圈之后 这就是第一名 和最后一名的差距
And after 72 laps, that's the difference between last and first.
C计划...
Plan C...
C计划就是战斗
Plan C's for combat.
战斗...
Combat, combat, combat.
那是驾驶升级版APX赛车的海耶斯
And that's Hayes in the upgraded APX.
在蒙扎站之后 车队被罚至最后一位
Now the team were penalized back to last place after Monza,
但现在他来了
but here he is,
从末位出发
coming from the cellar,
超过了新队友卢卡·科尔特斯
passing his new teammate, Luca Cortez.
在赛道弯中
Round the banking
海耶斯已经超过了奥康
Hayes has got past Ocon.
多么精彩的最后一圈
This is brilliant last lap drama.
多么精彩的结局啊
What a fantastic finish.
98987.53英镑
日本大奖赛
铃鹿赛道
海耶斯再次勇敢超车
Another fearless attack from Hayes.
这是APX GP车队展现实力的地方
And here's where the APX GP has found strength.
每圈光是靠弯道就能拿下0.3秒的优势
Three-tenths gained every lap, and in the corners alone.
在最后一圈奋起直追
Scrapping away on the last lap,
桑尼·海耶斯插入内线
Sonny Hayes gets the inside line
但无法完成超车
but he can't quite get past.
拉塞尔守住了第六的位置
George Russell will hang on here for sixth place,
但这是APX GP车队有史以来的最好成绩
but this is APX GP's best ever finish.
勇夺第七
It's a valiant seventh.
战斗 我爱这计划
Combat, I love it!
你每错过一场比赛 粉丝就淡忘你一分
Every race you miss, fans just forget you.
桑尼似乎总是领先一步
Sonny always seems to be one step ahead.
谁知道呢
You never know.
桑尼也许是故意捅你一刀 约书亚
Sonny may be a saboteur, Josh.
也许就为了取代你呢
He may be a saboteur.
墨西哥城大奖赛
罗德里格斯兄弟赛道
维斯塔潘和勒克莱尔并驾齐驱
...and they go wheel to wheel, Verstappen and Leclerc.
维斯塔潘将占据内线
Verstappen will have the inside.
佩雷兹要绕到外线去
Perez goes round the outside.
佩雷兹和勒克莱尔撞车了
Perez makes contact with Charles Leclerc
桑尼·海耶斯驾驶APX GP车队赛车
as Sonny Hayes threads that APX GP car
穿过混战
through the midfield.
真是留到了最后一刻才出手
Talk about leaving it late.
海耶斯从内线强势插入
Hayes squeezes through on the inside,
现在全力冲线
and with a run to the line now,
即将拿下队史最佳成绩
for their best position ever,
第五名
P5.
给研发团队发奖金吧
Give the design team a bonus,
升级后的赛车焕然一新
because the upgrade has completely changed this car.
如果约书亚·皮尔斯正在看比赛
And if Joshua Pearce is watching,
那他此刻一定在想
well, he must be thinking,
"如果当初没出事故会怎样?"
"What might have been?"
他把你当棋子 约书亚
He's treating you like a pawn, Josh.
要像骑士一样...
Be a knight! Be a knight! Be a knight!
几周前 谁会相信这种局面?
Who would have believed this weeks ago?
APX GP车队名震赛车界
Expensify APX GP has the racing world on notice.
APX! APX! APX!
快给1990年代打电话
Someone call the 1990s.
没找到桑尼·海耶斯也没关系
Sonny Hayes, if you missed him
他回来了
he's back.
比利时大奖赛
斯帕弗朗科尔尚赛道
最后一名请客吃早餐
Last one up buys breakfast.
看看谁回来了
Look who's back.
你好
Hello.
你回来真好 JP 我们想你了
Good to have you back, JP. We missed you.
APX! APX! APX! APX!
五盏红灯熄灭 比赛开始!
It's lights out and away we go!
开局不错
And it's a decent start,
所有车手都开得很文明
and everyone keeping it clean
顺利冲入La Source(1号弯)
as into La Source we go.
法拉利领先于红牛
Ferrari ahead of Red Bull,
两辆APX GP
but here the two APX GP cars
将作为一个团队协同作战
looking to work together as a team.
这是约书亚·皮尔斯的回归之战
It's a welcome back to the track for Joshua Pearce,
桑尼·海耶斯也很高兴见到队友
and Sonny Hayes glad to see him,
两人目前分列四五名
as they slice their way through positions four and five.
疾速冲入Kemmel直道
And onto the Kemmel Straight we go.
两人已接近极速
Now approaching top speed,
桑尼·海耶斯在约书亚·皮尔斯前方
Sonny Hayes ahead of Joshua Pearce.
他车祸后休养了一段时间
He's showing no ill effects
但现在看起来对他完全没有负面影响
from that time off after the crash.
赛车状态很好
The car's working beautifully.
两人合作无间
They're working as a team.
等等
But hang on,
皮尔斯紧紧跟在队友身
Pearce right on his tail
利用其尾流
using the slipstream.
他打算超车吗?
Is he about to try and overtake?
赛车来到连续弯
Into the chicane we go
双方车轮碰到了
and they touch wheels!
这是APX GP车队的灾难
This is disaster for APX
桑尼·海耶斯冲进了碎石区
as out goes Sonny Hayes and into the gravel!
混蛋
Assholes!
这个车队怎么了?
What is happening with this team?
复出后的第一场比赛
Their first race back together,
他们就撞到了一起
and they've run into each other.
-好样的 约书亚  -漂亮 朋友
-You did great, Joshua.  -Well done, mate.
你再这么搞 我就打掉你的牙齿
You pull that shit again, I will knock your teeth out.
谁也别想轻易超过我们 对吗?
No one gets past us without a fight, right?
你觉得很好笑? 你以为你明年能有席位?
Is this funny? You think you got a seat next year?
因为你刚把自己的机会减半了
'Cause you just cut your chances in half.
-你真是个蠢货  -是你自己不行...
-That's how dumb you are.  -You failed. You failed!
-我为什么要听你说话?  -嘿
-Why should I listen to you anyway, man?  -Hey.
听着 小子 我根本不在乎你
Look, man. I don't give two shits about you.
你想自毁前程 请随意
You wanna sabotage your career, you go right ahead.
我见过无数像你这样有才华的人昙花一现
I've seen hundreds of guys with your talent come and go.
没人在乎
No one cares!
但你要给鲁本搞破坏? 你要毁掉他的车队?
But you sabotage Ruben, who backed you? You sabotage his team?
我**不会让你这么干的！
I won't let you do it.
谢了 教练
Thanks, coach.
你**收拾好你的烂摊子
Get your shit together!
服了 真**傻*...
So stupid! God...
能总结一下你今天的比赛吗?
How would you sum up your race today?
很不错
It was good.
赛车状况良好 我觉得团队做得很好
You know, the car feels great. I think the team's done an amazing job.
可惜和桑尼撞车了
It's just a shame about the contact with Sonny.
这是我不想看到的
You hate to see that happen.
拉斯维加斯
感谢你
拉斯维加斯大奖赛
拉斯维加斯大道
桑尼启
晚9点在晚餐俱乐部
举行车队聚餐
-嗨 你好吗?  -嗨 你好吗?
-Hey, how are you doing?  -Hi, how are you?
好 好极了
Good. Sensational.
车队的其他人在哪?
Where's the team?
这边请 先生们
Right this way, gentlemen.
太好了 你们来了 坐吧
Brilliant, you made it. Come on. Sit down.
桑尼 你认识约书亚
Sonny, you know Joshua.
约书亚 这位是桑尼
Joshua, Sonny.
相信你们都听到谣言了
So I'm sure you both have heard the rumors.
如果你们不能创造奇迹 我们就要失业了
We all lose our jobs if you can't pull off a miracle,
首先请从别冲出赛道做起
and that's starting with staying on the bloody track.
JP养伤期间 我们的成绩良好
Well, we were doing just fine while JP was out.
我受伤是因为听了你的话
I was out because I was listening to you.
-没全听  -还有 请别叫我JP
-Ish.  -And please don't call me JP.
这是绰号 由不得你选
It's a nickname. You don't get to choose.
你自己的名字都一塌糊涂 是桑尼还是海耶斯?
And your name doesn't even make sense. Is it Sonny, is it Hayesie?
凯特 没人知道吧?
We don't know, do we, Kate?
老兄们
Lads.
我按要求把车改好了吧?
Have I not delivered you a car?
你们也得为我做一件事
So you can do one thing for me.
扑克牌
Cards.
拿出来吧 我知道你带着呢
Come on. I know you have 'em with ya.
我组织的团建 就得按我说的做
It's my team meeting, we're gonna do it my way.
-我们来打扑克  -拜托
-We're playing poker.  -Come on.
对 赢的人就是明天的头号车手
Yeah. Whoever wins gets to be our number one driver tomorrow,
如果我赢了 那由我来选
and if I win, I get to choose.
-他不是靠赌博为生的吗?  -是的
-Didn't he gamble for a living?  -Yeah.
结果他住在面包车上
Now he's living in a van.
得州扑克?
Texas Hold'em?
桑尼喜欢直言不讳
So, Sonny here likes straight talk.
桑尼 是不是?
Isn't that right, Sonny?
-是 听说是这样  -那我们谈谈
-Yeah, that's what I hear.  -So, let's talk.
谁先来?
Who wants to go first?
-我先来  -我先来
-I'll go first.  -I'll go first.
不行 我先来
No, I'll go first.
约书亚·皮尔斯和桑尼·海耶斯有什么不同?
What's the difference between Joshua Pearce and Sonny Hayes?
相差几十岁
A lot of decades.
-来之不易的经验  -生活在面包车上的经验?
-Hard-won experience.  -Of living in a van?
那是彻底的自由
Total freedom.
完全的一败涂地吧
Total failure.
真好意思说 这哥们还跟老妈一起住呢
Says the guy who still lives with his mom.
"手里不就攥着两对嘛！"
Says the guy with two pair.
-"手里不就攥着两对嘛?"  -别装了 我有满堂红? "
-Says the guy with trips.  -Says the guy with a full house.
我
Girl.
等等 我没和我妈住一起啊
Wait, I don't even live with my mum.
Okay.
她只是有时来给我做饭
She just cooks for me sometimes.
如果要给彼此建设性的意见  你们怎么说?
If you had any constructive criticism for each other, what would it be?
-别这么混蛋  -别这么蠢
-Don't be such an arsehole.  -Don't be such a dickhead.
很有建设性
That was constructive.
你大脑前额叶皮质发育不良
You have a deficient frontal cortex.
-什么?  -你不会做风险评估
-A what?  -You can't analyze risk.
不能全怪你 在你这个年龄 它还没完全发育
It's not all your fault, it's not fully formed yet at your age.
但等到你学会了耐心
But come the day you learn patience,
-不再那么幼稚 多想一想...  -耐心
-and stop being so immature, thinking  -Patience.
-耐心很好啊  -耐心
-Patience is good.  -Patience.
约书亚
Joshua.
他根本不在乎别人怎么说 只在乎他自己
He doesn't care about what anyone else has to say but himself.
他一进来就对我们发号施令 没有商量的余地
He just comes in and imposes his will on all of us with no discussion.
谁的话他都不听 我在努力 但他不听
He doesn't listen. I'm trying, but he doesn't listen.
-桑尼  -什么?
-Sonny?  -What?
Wow.
谁教你打牌的?
Who taught you how to play?
我爸喜欢赌博
My dad liked to gamble.
-他也下大赌注吗?  -他在我身上下了笔大的
-He make big bets too?  -Put a big one on me.
你们的父亲去世时 你们都多大?
How old were you when your fathers died?
抱歉
Sorry.
-13岁 -13岁
-Thirteen.  -Thirteen.
你们为什么赛车?
Why do you race?
钱、名气和免费的衣服
Money, fame and free clothes.
还在摆弄手机 不能放下吗?
Oh, my God, with the phone. Put the thing down, will ya?
你管他们说什么呢?
What do you care what they say?
你说得当然轻松 大家都喜欢你
Easy for you to say, they all love you.
那都是噪音 哥们
It's just noise, man.
专心开车
Drive the car.
你是优秀的车手
You're really good at it.
可能会成为伟大的车手
You might be great.
Yeah.
看吧? 明天的头号车手
Look at that, huh? Number one driver tomorrow.
在团建?
Bonding?
真好
Well, this is nice.
得走了 兄弟 赞助商在OMNIA有活动
We gotta go, mate. Sponsor party at OMNIA.
得把你拐走了
Gotta steal ya.
桑尼大叔 也欢迎你一起...
Uncle Sonny, you're welcome to come with...
谢谢 我不去了 明天有比赛
Thank you, I'm good. I have a race tomorrow.
-好吧 凯特?  -不了 谢谢
-Cool. Kate?  -No, thank you.
-走吧  -谢了 凯特
-Come on.  -Thanks for this, Kate.
走了
Come on, boy.
姑娘们 你们也许...
Girls, you might have to...
我们要去跳舞了 一起去跳舞?
We're gonna go dancing. Should we go dancing?
好啊 走啊
Come on! Let's go!
听着
Listen,
我们把话说清楚 好吗?
let's get this straight, okay?
赛季期间 我从不乱搞
I don't mess around during the season,
也从来不会和队友搞
and never with a member of my team,
能吸引我的只有获胜
and what I'm attracted to is winning.
而你刚刚输给一对五
And you just lost to a pair of fives.
嘿
Hey.
你是车手 对吗?
You're a driver, aren't you?
-是的  -哪支车队?
-Yeah.  -Which team?
APX GP车队
APX GP.
你能介绍我认识赛恩斯吗?
Can you introduce me to Carlos Sainz?
我去叫他
I'll go get him.
嘿...
Hey. Hey.
嘿 为什么他们说这地方很奇怪?
Oi, why do they say this place is weird?
-我喜欢这里 兄弟  -你开心我就开心 哥们
-I like this, bruv.  -Glad you're having fun, man.
保重 我要走了 好吗?
Be safe. I'm gonna leave, yeah?
我说我走了
I said I'm gonna cut.
-等等 别啊 你这才刚到!  -我今天没劲儿
-Wait, no, no, no. You just got here!  -I just... I'm not feeling it.
什么意思? 你才刚到 兄弟 约书亚
What do you mean? You just got here, bro. Josh!
嘿
Hey.
我不该喝龙舌兰的
I shouldn't drink tequila.
昨晚是鲁本的主意?
Last night was Ruben's idea?
对 前一半是
Yeah, the first part.
-好吧  -后一半不是
-Well...  -Not the second!
好了
Come on.
桑尼 你来干什么?
Why are you here, Sonny, huh?
理由不算精彩
Not much of a story.
Okay.
我来是为了证明所有人都错了
I'm here to prove everyone wrong.
我的前夫、前老板
My ex, my old boss,
大学一年级的物理教授
my first-year uni physics professor.
-那个混蛋  -是啊
-That bastard.  -Yeah.
但我们必须赢 我才能证明他们都错了
And until we win, I haven't.
所以很不幸 我现在得指望你了
So, unfortunately, I now rely on you.
我本来会成为世界冠军
I was gonna be world champion.
有史以来最优秀的车手
The best there ever was.
我只是个孩子 却已在赛道上与偶像并肩驰骋
I'm just a kid and I'm on the track with my idols,
塞纳、曼塞尔、普罗斯特
Senna, Mansell, Prost.
我的速度很快
And I am quick.
无所畏惧
I'm fearless.
我就是下一任车王
I was next.
然后...
And then...
一切都被夺走了
it was all taken away.
那场车祸?
The crash, huh?
我失去了席位、钱、理智 还有...
So I lost my seat, my money, my sanity, my...
自我
myself, really.
成了一个满腔愤怒、怨气冲天的混蛋
Just became this angry, resentful shithead.
自己都嫌弃自己
Not someone I'm particularly proud of.
直到有一天 我才明白 自己真正失去的是什么
Till one day, I realized what I had really lost,
并不是冠军头衔、奖杯 也不是纪录
and it wasn't the titles, or the trophies, or the records,
是我对赛车的热爱
it was my love for racing.
于是我又开始比赛
So I started driving.
赛车、赛道都无所谓 不需要任何观众
Didn't matter the car, the circuit, didn't need anyone to watch.
只要握住方向盘 我就所向披靡
Just as long as I was behind the wheel, I was good.
有时...
Sometimes...
怎么了?
What?
说啊
Come on.
很少见 但有时 在赛车里会有这么一瞬间
It's rare, but sometimes, there's this moment in the car
一切都安静下来
where everything goes quiet,
我的心跳变慢
my heartbeat slows,
非常平静
it's peaceful,
我可以看到一切 任何人...
and I can see everything, and no one...
都不能触及我一丝一毫
no one can touch me.
我每次坐进赛车 都在追寻这样的瞬间
And I am chasing that moment every time I get in the car.
我不知道还能否再次如愿 但我很想找到它
I don't know when I'll find it again, but, man, I want to.
非常想
I want to.
因为在那个瞬间里 我在飞翔
'Cause in that moment, I'm flying.
凯特
Kate.
-鲁本  -他在哪?
-Ruben.  -Where is he?
谁在哪?
Where's who?
你说什么呢?
What are you talking about?
鲁本 开什么玩笑?
Ruben, seriously?
首先 你怎么敢这样想?
One, how dare you?
其次 我尊重职业边界感
Two, I respect professional boundaries.
第三...
And three...
第三 好吧 他在阳台上
Three, yeah, he's on the balcony.
-你起得真早  -换衣服
-Well, you're up early.  -Get dressed.
-怎么了?  -他们要查我们的车
-Yeah, what's going on?  -They're coming for our car.
我有责任告知你 我们收到了匿名举报
It's my duty to inform you  that we've received an anonymous tip
称你们升级后的底板存在违规情况
that your upgraded floor is in violation.
谁举报的?
From who?
我不能说
I can't say.
先生 我们早就提交图纸了
Sir, we submitted drawings long ago.
对吧?
Right?
你全都批准了
And you approved them all.
关键在于 你们参赛用的零件 是否是在你们的工厂之外研发的
It's whether the parts you're racing with were developed outside of your facility.
什么?真是疯了
What? That's insane.
我们收到的文件显示 这方面存在一些问题
Based on the paperwork we've received, there are concerns.
等等 你从哪弄来的这些? 这都是内部文档
Hang on, where'd you get these? These are internal documents.
我们车队从不违规 先生 没有的事...
This team doesn't break any rules, sir. No, no.
-我对此持保留意见  -文档是可以伪造的
-I'll take that with a pinch of salt.  -Someone can fabricate documents.
你们的车要经过审核
Your car's under review.
-流程你们都懂  -什么?
-You know the procedure.  -What?
除非你们换上先前批准的部件 否则不能参赛
You cannot race unless you substitute the previously approved components.
-不行  -你是说我们之前的设计?
-No!  -Do you mean our old design?
破烂货
A shitbox!
难以置信
No me lo puedo creer.
过去两年你干什么去了? 偏偏现在跑出来?
Where were you the last two years? Why now?
因为我们有可能赢? 是不是?
Because we might actually win a race? Is that it?
这可不是赛车 先生 这是商业间谍活动
This is not car racing, sir, this is like corporate espionage!
抱歉...别走
I'm sorry. I'm sorry. Come here.
我跟你说话呢 先生
I'm talking to you! Sir!
没有升级 我们就完了
Without the upgrade, we're screwed.
桑尼 算了 老老实实起步吧
Sonny, let it go. Focus on a clean start.
老实永远赢不了
We'll never win clean.
我们别违规行不行?
Can we just not break any rules?
好啊 但规矩总是针对我们 不是吗?
Yeah, the rules are always against us though, aren't they?
让他们安全跑完第一圈
Get them safe through lap one.
桑尼 我们只需平平安安 明白吗?
Sonny, we just need to keep it in one piece. Okay?
桑尼?
Sonny?
-嘿 怎么回事?  -不知道
-Oi, what the hell?  -I don't know!
桑尼怎么了?
What's wrong with Sonny?
约书亚 好了 专心点 你没事
Joshua, yep. Keep focused. You're still good.
他干什么?
What's he doing?
他在带着怒气开车
He's driving angry.
不好 很不好
Not good. It's not good.
桑尼 你得让轮胎持久一点
Sonny, we need to make these tires last.
开稳一点
Take it easy.
不好 他把赛车调成排位赛模式了
No, he's put the car in qualifying mode.
这样电池很快就会耗光 让他调回来
He's gonna run the battery down. Tell him to put it back.
桑尼 你现在是排位赛模式 怎么回事?
Sonny, you're now in qualifying mode. What's going on?
桑尼 怎么了?
Sonny, what's happening?
...在拉斯维加斯大道上
...blasting along Las Vegas Boulevard,
以338公里的时速飞驰
210 miles an hour.
现在重刹
Hard on the brakes now,
进入连续弯
and into the chicane.
佩雷兹在桑尼·海耶斯前方
Sergio Perez, ahead of Sonny Hayes,
但海耶斯的出弯更快
but that's a mega exit from Hayes.
他要追上佩雷兹了
He's gotta gain on Sergio Perez,
正在逼近
and he's closing.
一米接一米 一寸接一寸地追赶
Meter by meter. Inch by inch.
这里要赌一把吗?
Is this the place to take a gamble?
海耶斯从外线发起进攻
Hayes attacks round the outside.
不...
No! No!
我们为什么赛车?
Why do we do this?
网球有什么不好?
What's wrong with tennis, huh?
高尔夫也不错啊
Or golf.
是吧?
Right?
唉...
Christ.
我们彻底疯了
We are totally insane.
"C5颈椎骨折
"C5 neck fracture.
脊髓挫伤
Spinal contusion.
压缩性胸椎骨折
Compressed thoracic vertebrae.
再受钝性创伤 可能会导致失明
Further blunt force impact trauma likely to result in vision loss,
瘫痪甚至死亡"
paralysis, death."
他们可真会用好消息来开场啊
Really lead with the good news, don't they?
这是30年前的病历报告
This is a report from 30 years ago.
你为什么不告诉我?
Why didn't you tell me?
你根本不该再次赛车的 桑尼
You never should have raced again, Sonny.
如果你死在赛道上 你觉得我会作何感受?
How do you think I'd feel if you die on the track?
为摩纳哥站复仇
Revenge for Monaco.
我不是在跟你开玩笑!
It's not a joke!
出事的话 该负责的人是我 桑尼
It's me who's liable, Sonny.
别以为有什么狗屁空子 能让你钻了后全身而退
And don't think there's some bullshit loophole to get you out of this.
-没有  -鲁本 我们是车手
-No.  -Ruben, we're drivers.
不再是了 抱歉 真的不是了
We are not drivers, not anymore. I'm sorry. We're not.
我们是失败者
We're losers.
我们是一对愚蠢
We're a pair of dumb,
感情用事
sentimental,
破产的失败者
broke losers.
好 你被开除了
Okay. You're off the team.
你的面包车在停车场 你的东西都在上面 还有...
Your van is in the garage with all your stuff in it, and...
我真不该把你卷进来的 桑尼
I never should have pulled you into this, Sonny.
对不起
I'm sorry.
鲁本 等等
Ruben, wait!
我需要赛车
I need this.
没人能开一辈子车 桑尼 就算是你也不行
No one drives forever, Sonny. Not even you.
皮帕 调出蒙扎站 像事故那天一样 雨天
Pippa, load up Monza. Just like it happened. In the rain.
约书亚 桑尼说等直道 一号弯前的直道
Joshua, Sonny says wait for the straight, the straight into turn one.
请再来一次
Run it again, please.
...等直道 一号弯前的直道
...wait for the straight, the straight into turn one.
请再来一次
Run it again, please.
一号弯前的直道
The straight into turn one.
桑尼
Sonny.
F1拉斯维加斯大奖赛
明年见
嗨 你没去阿布扎比?
Hey. You're not in Abu Dhabi?
我今晚飞过去 我...
I fly out tonight. I...
对 我想找你聊聊
Yeah, I wanted to catch you.
听我说
So, listen.
你我都知道 董事会从一开始就想卖掉APX
We both know that the board's wanted to unload APX from the start,
但是没错 然后你来了
but, yeah, then you rode into town,
提升了我们的整体形象 现在我...
raised our whole profile, and now I've...
对 我...有不少买家等着出手呢
Yeah, I've got... I've got buyers lining up.
-好吧  -我得跟你说实话 哥们
-Uh-huh.  -Gotta be honest with you, man,
我本以为你会是压垮骆驼的最后一根稻草
I thought you were gonna be the... the final nail in the coffin.
但我现在看懂战术了
But now I see the play.
我希望你加入团队
And I want you as part of the package.
什么团队?
What sort of package?
我已经谈好了一笔交易 之后由我来接手车队
I've set up a sale where I run the team,
你留在队里负责战术
and keep you on for strategy,
甚至可以当领队
maybe even team principal.
有了那笔交易的钱 我能让你发大财
With the money from that deal, I can make you a very rich man.
重点是
Here's the thing.
随着...规则的不断更改
With the... the changing regulations,
全新的奔驰动力单元 凯特的空气动力套件 还有两位新车手
... new Mercedes power unit, Kate's aero, two new drivers...
我们明年真的有机会冲击总冠军
we've got a real shot at the championship next year.
那鲁本呢?
What about Ruben?
别担心
Don't worry.
你懂的
You know.
我们不会让他难堪的
We won't embarrass him.
我们会给他...挂个名 或者当品牌大使
We'll keep him on with a... with a title, or brand ambassador...
总有他的位置
You know, something.
我有最终话语权?
And I get final say?
你可千万别变
Don't change a thing.
按自己的想法去做
Do what you do, man.
这挺讽刺的
And that's the irony here.
董事会当初同意请你来
You know, the board originally approved your hire
因为我们认为你会帮我们输
because we thought you'd help us lose.
-抱歉 害你紧张了  -嘿
-Sorry to make you sweat.  -Hey.
这是我的手机号
That's my number.
去跟你的人聊聊吧
Talk to your people.
但是比赛一结束 我就要敲定合同
But right after the race, I wanna lock down the deal, okay?
-这周天?  -很好
-So, by Sunday?  -Perfect.
听着 这可以让你成为传奇
Listen, this thing can be your legacy, you know?
成为F1世界冠军
An F1 champion.
不就是你一直梦寐以求的吗?
What you always wanted, right?
那些文档是你伪造的吧?
It was you who forged those documents, wasn't it?
-你可真是个狠人  -嘿 我是赢家
-You're a killer, man, aren't you?  -Hey. I'm a winner.
你不是吗?
Aren't you, huh?
好了
Okay.
对了 你的后背怎么样?
Hey. How's the back?
好多了
Better.
我认识个很厉害的人 我会为你牵线的
I've got an amazing guy. I'll hook you up.
孤注一掷
Hail Mary.
F1拉斯维加斯大奖赛
明年见
阿布扎比大奖赛
亚斯码头赛道
最后一场比赛
你还好吗?
You good?
听着 妈 我有件事要跟你说
Listen, Mum, I've gotta tell you something.
蒙扎站 车祸前 那个动作是我自己决定的
In Monza, right before the crash, it was my decision to make the move.
桑尼其实叫我等等的
Sonny actually told me to wait.
家人们
Family.
我一直在跟印地赛车的人联系
I've been working the phones with IndyCar,
我觉得能帮你争取到一次试车 兄弟
and I think I can get you a test drive, bruv.
-你好 阿姨  -嗨
-Hello, Auntie.  -Hi.
他们在努力吸引新的消费群体
They're trying to pull in a new demographic, obviously.
女士们都喜欢他的笑容
And the ladies love that smile.
我们还能要点额外福利 比如机票和车
And we can throw in some incentives, like flights and cars.
听着 卡什 你可以走了 我今天不需要你
Listen, Cash, you can go. I don't need you today.
不行 兄弟 你接下来要接受采访
Nah, mate. You got media next.
无所谓 尽管罚好了
I don't care. They can fine me.
而且
Besides,
这不是我赛车的初衷 对吗?
that's not why I'm doing it, right?
约书亚 从明天开始 我们根本没车可赛了
Josh, starting tomorrow, we're not "doing it" anywhere.
都是噪音罢了
It's all just noise.
媒体、互动、粉丝
Media, engagement, followers.
听着 我得把心思放在比赛上
Listen, I've gotta focus on the race.
阿姨 你劝劝他
Auntie, please.
随他去吧
Well, you heard the man.
-成交  -成交
-Deal.  -Deal.
-唷  -嗨
-Yo.  -Hey.
-嗨  -嗨
-Hi.  -Hey.
各位 怎么了?
Guys, what's happening?
车被封存监管 在等国际汽联来剪开封条
Parc fermé. Waiting for FIA to cut the seals.
好啊
Oh, good.
-那我们有时间了  -有时间做什么?
-We got time then.  -For what?
做...
For...
不是吧...
No, no, no.
欢迎来到围场俱乐部 这里是为我们最尊贵的宾客而设
Welcome to the Paddock Club, for our most valued guests.
请随意喝点什么 就像在自己家一样
Please grab a drink, make yourselves at home,
尽享F1最佳观赛视角
and enjoy the very best view there is of Formula 1.
怎么样?好
Okay? Okay.
嘿 各位 别停 继续跑
Hey, guys, don't stop! Keep going!
不会吧
No way.
天啊 这里简直像个停尸房
Jesús, it's like a morgue around here.
你怎么来的?
How'd you get here?
高级经济舱
Premium economy.
什么?这是什么?
What? What is this?
这就是我钻的狗屁空子
Well, that's my bullshit loophole.
哦 得了吧 我都懒的去读
Oh, no, forget it. I'm not even going to read that.
这是一份正式的的法律文件，出自一个地道的'蒂华纳律师'之手
That is a real legal document from a real Tijuana lawyer,
本人主动声明 放弃追究你和你的公司
waiving all liability to you
对这场比赛、对我本人 以及对我自己的一切责任
and your company vis-à-vis this race, myself, and me.
还有就是...
And...
因为你拖欠我最后一站的工资 严格来说 我还是这个车队的一员
since you owe me my last paycheck, technically I'm still on this team.
凯特 那台破烂货呢?
Kate, where's the shitbox?
国际汽联确认 文档都是伪造的
The FIA confirmed that the documents were forged,
是车队内部的人发给他们的
and they were sent by someone from APX.
好 我不在乎你的空子 真的
Okay, I don't care about your loophole. I don't.
这是我的车 不许你开
That is my car. You are not racing it.
-鲁本  -不行 桑尼
-Ruben.  -No, Sonny.
听着
Listen,
我不能让你比赛
I can't let you do that.
真的不能
I can't.
明白吗?
Okay?
如果此生做的最后一件事是开那辆车 那我也不枉此生了
If the last thing I do is drive that car, I will take that life, man.
无怨无悔
A thousand times.
我们赢不了的
We can't win.
不试试当然赢不了
We can't if we don't try.
你为什么从来不看那张牌?
How come you never look at the card?
什么牌?
What card?
欢迎来到发车格的最后几位
Welcome to the very final spots on the grid.
一如既往
And as ever,
我们从后往前介绍
we'll go from last to first.
第22位 这里有一则突发新闻
And breaking news here in P22,
因为我们听说 APX GP车队决定
because we're hearing the APX GP team
-嘿 彼得  -怎么了?
-Hey, Peter.  -Yeah?
那是你的车手 不是吗?
That's your guy. Isn't it?
由桑尼·海耶斯上场
have made being replaced by Sonny Hayes,
他甚至没跟车队一同前往阿布扎比
who didn't even make the trip to Abu Dhabi...
失陪一下 非常抱歉
Will you excuse me for one second? I'm really sorry.
根据规则要求
Now, the rules require that
他必须从最后一位起步
that he has to start at the back of the pack.
借过 搞什么?
Excuse me. What the hell?
什么?
What?
你还拿着我的手机吗?
You still got my phone?
桑尼·海耶斯
-祝好运  -你也是 詹姆斯
-Good luck today.  -You too, James.
借过 嘿 桑尼...
Excuse me. Hey, Sonny. Sonny!
嘿 听着 我知道我们有过分歧
Hey, look, I know we've had our differences,
-但这是你最后一场F1比赛  -查斯 就是他
1but look, this is your last F1 race.  -Chaz! This guy.
你有什么想...
Any thought...
这是什么?
What's that?
天啊
Bloody hell.
Bloody hell!
拼一把?
Elbows out?
拼一把
Elbows out !
即将在阿布扎比站迎来赛季收官战
All set for our season finale here in Abu Dhabi
五盏红灯熄灭 比赛开始
where it's lights out And away we go.
约书亚·皮尔斯起步不错
Good start there for Joshua Pearce.
车手们在主直道全油门疾驰
Drivers jockeying for position
抢夺前排位置
as we head full-throttle down the main straight
冲向一号弯
and into turn one.
第一个弯不好过
Tricky first corner,
阿斯顿马丁 和小红牛车队的车手走大了
and going wide, the Aston Martin and the AlphaTauri
皮尔斯前进了两位
as Pearce picks up two places.
皮尔斯表现得非常成熟
Yes, Pearce showing some real maturity there.
他预见了糟糕的局面
He saw a bad situation before it happened,
这次起跑堪称完美
and he's off to a great start.
想都别想
Don't even think about it.
Alpine从内线切入
Here comes the Alpine down the inside.
撞上了
Contact!
海耶斯刚出院三天
And three days out of hospital,
这下一定很痛
Hayes will feel that.
提升排位啊 各位 我们还没结束呢
Gained places, guys. We're alive.
希望他的赛车没有受损
I hope he hasn't damaged the car,
尽管如此
but despite everything,
第一圈的成绩依然不错
it's still a great first lap.
海耶斯已经来到第16
It is! Hayes in P16.
他的队友皮尔斯来到了第九
Pearce, his teammate, up to P9.
第11圈
红牛、梅奔和法拉利领跑
Red Bull, Mercedes and Ferrari holding on to the lead.
APX在中游
APX in the midfield.
看看他们能否扰乱战局
Let's see if they can do anything to shake up this race.
距离第一差多少?
Gap to leader?
15秒
Fifteen seconds.
让JP保持20秒内的距离...
Keep JP plus 20 seconds. Plus 20.
-进站时长  -你懂的
-Length of a pit stop.  -You know why.
桑尼·海耶斯很忙
It's a busy race for Sonny Hayes,
现在凯文·马格努森来到了身后
and now here comes Kevin Magnussen
伺机而动
looking to make a move.
可能会导致麻烦
And this could spell trouble.
这两人曾有过节
There's history between these two.
每次都是硬碰硬 针锋相对 互不相让
Often, the irresistible force meets the immovable object.
马格努森想从内线寻找机会
And Magnussen, looking down the inside,
进站...
Box, box. Box, box, box.
车轮锁死 撞到了海耶斯
locks up and hits Hayes.
收到 准备换硬胎
Copy, coming in for hards.
该死
Damn.
慢即是稳 稳即是快 来了 伙计们
Slow is smooth. Smooth is fast. Here we go, boys.
海耶斯驶出维修区
Hayes exit the pits.
他不得不进站
He had to come in
因为轮胎受损
He had to come in because of that damage to his tire.
但约书亚·皮尔斯怎么办?
But what of Joshua Pearce?
APX GP车队将如何安排他?
Where do APX GP go with him?
各位 我进站吗?计划呢?
Guys, am I boxing? What's the plan?
C计划...继续比赛...
Plan C, Plan C. Stay out. Stay out.
-混乱  -收到
-Chaos. -Copy that.
约书亚为桑尼压住领跑集团的车速 桑尼也为他这样做
Joshua slows down the leaders for Sonny. Sonny does the same for him.
皮尔斯继续比赛
Pearce stays out.
这个战术APX本赛季前就用过
It's a strategy that APX have used before this season.
暂时可以帮他们保住排位
It helps them with track position for now,
但他们必须保护好轮胎
but they gotta keep these tires alive.
我们只能这样才能咬紧其他车手
It's the only way we keep this close.
我们还需要运气
And then we need luck.
我早就想到了
I'm way ahead of ya.
第25圈
比赛进行到第25圈
Lap 25,
除了约书亚之外 其他车手都已进站
and every driver so far has pitted, bar one.
他暂时领跑比赛
And he leads the race.
约书亚·皮尔斯在前面控制着速度
Joshua Pearce controlling the pace out in front.
让他的队友海耶斯
And that gives his teammate, Hayes,
有机会保住中游的位置
a chance to maintain his position in the midfield
尽管他的赛车 发生碰撞、爆胎、多一次停站
despite the contact, puncture and pit stop.
他们配合得天衣无缝
They're working really well together.
JP情况如何?
How's JP doing up there?
他压着领跑集团呢 下一段直道可以开启DRS 桑尼
He's keeping the leaders at bay. DRS active next straight, Sonny.
收到
Got it.
进入直道尾端
Onto the back straight,
他的新升级套件表现不错
he's enjoying this new upgrade,
开启DRS 成功超越了嘉斯利
and he's got DRS, and he's got Pierre Gasly.
桑尼·海耶斯上升到了第15位
Sonny Hayes up into P15.
桑尼 你现在速度很快 继续冲刺
Sonny, you have got the pace. Keep pushing.
皮尔斯一直在领跑 表现出色
Pearce has been doing a great job out front
但是他的轮胎已经磨损
despite the used tires,
他即将被超越
but that moment is nearly over now.
维斯塔潘从内线超了过去
Verstappen up the inside and he's through.
约书亚·皮尔斯在第一段表现优异
Fabulous first stint from Joshua Pearce.
维斯塔潘超了过去
Max has passed,
但他的麻烦还没完
and his troubles don't end there.
接着是勒克莱尔
Here comes Charles Leclerc.
又一次超越
It's another overtake.
皮尔斯不再领跑 掉到了第三
Pearce lost the lead and drops now to P3.
抱歉 各位 我的后胎不行了
Sorry, guys. My rear tires are shot.
收到 JP 进站...
Copy that. Box, JP. Box, box.
皮尔斯把轮胎用到了极限
Pearce stretching those tires to the limit.
短暂的痛苦 是为了最后的胜利
Short-term pain for long-term gain.
他驶离维修区
And he exits the pits.
换上了新胎
And he exits the pits. He'll have fresher tires.
可以在比赛的后半段发起进攻
He can now attack in the second half of the race.
桑尼 三位领跑车手还在使用硬胎
Sonny, the three leaders are still on hards.
一定会再次停车 现在是他们的进站窗口
They're gonna have to stop again. This is their pit window.
有人会抢先进站造成时间差 我得抓住这个时机
One of the leaders is gonna undercut. I need to be there when they do.
第三的法拉利 皮帕 他能超过去吗?
P3 Ferrari. Pippa, can he beat it to one?
要看他的进站时间了
Depends on their stop.
undercut对法拉利有用吗?
Will the undercut work for Ferrari?
5.8秒 他必须赶出半秒来
Five point eight. He needs to pick up half a second.
桑尼 你要赶出半秒来 快...
Sonny, you need half a second. Go, go, go, go, go.
桑尼·海耶斯加速了
And Sonny Hayes is on the charge.
法拉利从维修区杀出来了
Under the track goes the Ferrari.
桑尼·海耶斯通过了一号弯
Through the first corner goes Sonny Hayes.
双方并驾齐驱 只差分毫
It's neck and neck. It's really tight.
桑尼·海耶斯刚好卡在赛恩斯前面
Sonny Hayes is just ahead of Carlos Sainz.
好 漂亮
Yes! Come on!
APX GP车队的战术目前是成功的
It's worked so far for APX GP.
但他们的麻烦还没结束
But their trouble's not over.
赛恩斯位于内线
Down the inside,
有机会 他上了
there's a chance for Carlos Sainz, and he takes it.
但他锁死了
But he locks up.
法拉利滑出去了
The Ferrari goes wide
桑尼·海耶斯说
and Sonny Hayes says,
"非常感谢"
"Thank you very much indeed."
他们怎么这么靠近第一名?
How are they staying so close to the lead?
他们...在相互配合
They're... They're working together.
两辆APX GP位于前十名
Two APX cars in the top 10,
但距离比赛结束还有很久
but still a long way to go.
第38圈
还剩20圈
Twenty laps remaining,
APX GP车队的排名不断攀升
and APX has worked their way up the order.
现在我们处于最后一次进站窗口
We're now at the final pit stop window.
这是我们夺冠的机会 一定要确保JP比他们快
This is our chance for P1. Make sure JP beats them out.
汉密尔顿和勒克莱尔进入维修区
Hamilton and Leclerc come into the pits,
但皮尔斯还在赛道上
but Pearce stays out.
-告诉我 我能追上他们吗?  -能 他们刚出站
-Talk to me. Can I catch 'em?  -Yep. They're just coming out.
现在加速...快...
Push now. Push now. Push, push.
收到 加速了
Copy. Pushing.
将会很靠近
This is gonna be close.
约书亚·皮尔斯正在一点点领先
Joshua Pearce inching ahead. Staying ahead.
这场比赛第二次来到了领跑位
For the second time in this race, he leads.
冲啊
-Let's go!
你在领跑 约书亚
You are P1, Joshua.
但皮尔斯将很难守住位置
But Pearce will have a hard time holding them off
汉密尔顿和勒克莱尔都换上了新胎
with Hamilton and Leclerc on fresh tires.
第54圈
还剩四圈
Four laps to go.
桑尼·海耶斯排在第4
Sonny Hayes is in P4.
落后队友五秒
He's five seconds behind his teammate,
但两人用的都是旧胎
but both are on old tires.
他们现在几乎不可能提升排位了
There's little chance they'll gain any places now.
汉密尔顿来了
And here's Hamilton
在五号弯对皮尔斯发起攻击
attacking Pearce into turn five.
超了过去
And he's through.
没人会再停了 而我们的轮胎比他们多跑了九圈
Nobody has to stop again and our tires are nine laps older.
勒克莱尔也超了过去
And Leclerc attacks and passes.
皮尔斯的轮胎彻底完蛋了
Pearce's tires are absolutely finished.
他已经无计可施
There was nothing he could do about that.
抱歉 各位 我没办法了
I'm sorry, guys. I've got nothing left.
这一整年 APX GP车队都是舆论的焦点
It's been the APX GP story all year long.
他们冒了很多险
Plenty of risks.
这是一个精彩的翻盘故事
A great underdog story,
但我们知道
but we know, Martin,
只有天赋才能成就冠军
only talent crowns a champion.
没有抓地力 轮胎不行了
Losing grip. Tires are gone.
对 很不幸 局势对他们不利
Yeah. Sadly, the deck's been stacked against them
现在他们已无技可施
and now they're out of cards to play.
还没结束吧?
It ain't over, right?
没有 但什么都无法改变了 这是世上最糟糕的感觉
No, but nothing can change. It's the worst feeling in the world.
拉塞尔发起攻击
George Russell on the attack.
海耶斯试图
Hayes looking to defend,
在左弯时防守
through the left-hander they go...
撞车了!
And there's contact!
海耶斯转了一圈
Hayes is spun round
撞上了护墙
and into the barrier.
撞得很严重
That's a big one.
-太好了...  -不
-Fucking yes, yes, yes.  -Oh, no.
对 不好
Yeah, no.
赛道上到处都是碎片
There's debris all over the race track
护墙也遭到了严重的损坏
and substantial damage to the barriers.
赛会干事不得不出示红旗
The stewards have no choice but to red flag this race.
奇迹
Miracle.
说到损坏
And speaking of damage, Martin,
海耶斯只有在能将赛车开到赛道另一边
Hayes will only be allowed to continue in this race
并回到维修区的情况下
if he can get his car all the way around the circuit
才能继续参加这场比赛
and back to the pit lane.
桑尼...能开回来吗?
Sonny. Sonny, can you get it back?
我会开回来的 推也要推回来
I'll get it back. I'll get it back if I have to push it back.
加油 桑尼 慢慢开
Come on, Sonny. Nice and easy.
他还在开...
He's still going. He's still going.
JP 出红旗了
JP, red flag.
红旗 回来
Red flag. Come in.
我们还有戏 兄弟
We are still alive,  hermano
红旗
Red flag!
桑尼·海耶斯竟然把车开回维修区了
And somehow Sonny Hayes has got his car back to the pit lane.
这是奇迹  -我知道...
-It's a miracle.  -I know! I know.
我之前从来没见过
Never seen one until now.
到家了 好样的 加油
Home free. Good girl. Let's go.
换新软胎 两辆都换
New softs, both cars.
把胎压调高 准备冲刺三圈
Raise the tire pressure for three quick laps.
队友们 该造车了
Team, time to build a car.
来聊聊红旗的规则吧
Red flag rules then.
车队可以对车辆进行调整
The teams can make changes.
也可以对赛车进行维修
They can make repairs to their cars.
但只能在维修区进行
But only in that pit lane.
而留给APX GP车队修理的时间只有十分钟
And with only ten minutes to make repairs,
他们面临的任务十分艰巨
APX GP has their work cut out.
所有赛车都能换上新胎
And all cars can fit a fresh set of tires
准备冲刺三圈
for what will be a three-lap sprint.
-道奇...我们赶得上吗?  1我不知道...
-Dodge! Dodge, are we gonna make it?  -I don't know. I don't know.
没犯规 不是我的错 这次不是
That was clean. That wasn't me. Not this time.
"这次不是"? 你跟赛会干事说去
"Not this time"? Tell that to the stewards.
看回放啊
Check the replay.
我来 你去抬那个角
I got this. Lift that corner.
我不用...
I'm good. I'm good, I'm good. I'm good.
赛事干事将要检查
What the stewards will be looking at
海耶斯在与拉塞尔发生碰撞时
whether Hayes went off completely
是完全离开了赛道
or kept at least one tire on track
还是至少有一只轮胎还在赛道上
during the contact with Russell.
-唷 还好吗?  -很好
-Yo, you good?  -Yeah, good.
听着 你当时在赛道上
Listen, you were on track.
对 那是属于你的弯道 第三、第四位 加油
Yeah, it was your corner. P3 and P4. Let's go!
鉴于海耶斯名声在外
Given Hayes's reputation,
他们会非常仔细的查看回放
they'll be looking at this really, really closely.
正在调查: 7号桑尼与63号拉塞尔
在1号弯的事故 - 导致的碰撞
我不认为这么快会有结果
I'm not expecting a quick decision.
拜托 显然应该判罚
Come on, that's clearly a penalty.
就是...我们也不想啊
Like... I mean, not that that's what we want,
但客观上讲 这人可是惯犯
but, like, objectively, that's the guy.
-天啊 不能这样结束  -只是暂停而已
-Oh, man. It can't end this way.  -It's just a time-out.
就像过去的30年 现在要看掌管赛车的神怎么说了
Like the last 30 years. It's in the hands of the racing gods now.
一定可以的 一定可以的!...
Gotta believe. Gotta believe.
维修区忙得热火朝天
Plenty going on here in the pits.
看啊 新尾翼
Oh, look. Here comes the new wing.
这可是大工程
This is a massive job.
是的 但赛车能撑住最后三圈吗?
Yeah, but will the car hold together for the remaining three laps?
护墙看起来已经修好了
Well, that barrier looks okay now.
马修正在清扫赛道上的碎片
The marshals just sweeping the last few bits of debris off the track,
时间一分一秒地过去
and the clock continues to tick down.
是的 还有不到两分钟
Yeah, it's just over two minutes
比赛就会恢复了
until this race gets underway again.
JP, JP!
三圈是很长一段时间
Three laps. Three laps is a lifetime.
去赢下冠军吧
Go win this thing.
嘿 桑尼...有空吗?
Hey, Sonny. Sonny, you got a minute?
我们把车修好了
We got you a car.
你们真棒 谢谢
You rock. Thank you.
因为APX GP车队在排位赛里没有杀进前十
Because APX GP didn't make the top 10 in qualifying,
所以他们有一套全新的软胎
they have a new set of soft tires available,
能比排在前面的几辆车开得更快
which will give them extra speed over the cars ahead of them
因为他们的软胎是旧的
on the used soft tires.
这个红旗是救命稻草
This red flag is a lifeline.
几乎让人觉得这是桑尼一手策划的
You'd almost wonder if Sonny didn't engineer it.
等等 只有我们的车在用全新胎
But wait, we're the only cars on fresh tires
因为我们昨天的排位赛成绩太烂?
because we sucked in qualifying yesterday?
所以没机会用新软胎
Never got the chance to use them.
有时候输了反而会赢
Sometimes when you lose, you win.
-毫无道理  -是桑尼说的
-That don't make no sense.  -It's a Sonny thing.
维修区尽头的灯变绿了
Light at the end of the pit lane is green.
我们迎来今晚的第二圈暖胎圈
We're off on our second formation lap of the evening,
比赛一旦重新开始
and when this race resumes，
将是一场史诗级的冲刺对决
this is gonna be an epic sprint.
汉密尔顿、勒克莱尔、皮尔斯、海耶斯
Hamilton, Leclerc, Pearce, Hayes.
是前四的车手
That's the top four.
桑尼 赛会干事发来消息了
Sonny, we just heard from the stewards.
见鬼 现在吗?
Goddamn it. Now?
我们在讨论要不要告诉你
We're debating whether to tell you.
卡什帕说"要"  但凯特说"不要"
Kaspar says, "Yes," but Kate says, "Don't."
她说你生气的时候开得快
She says you're fast when you're angry.
告诉她:"干得漂亮"
Tell her, "Job well done."
消息出来了
And here's news.
赛会干事决定
Stewards have made their decision.
第55圈 海耶斯和拉塞尔的撞车
That Lap 55 collision between Hayes and Russell
赛事干事: 对1号弯涉及7号桑尼和63号拉塞尔的事故
进行了审查，无需进一步调查 - 碰撞被判定为赛道事故 。
被判定为赛道事故
is ruled a racing incident.
不用继续调查
No further investigation.
桑尼
Sonny.
这是你的机会 桑尼 去完成比赛吧
That was your line, Sonny. Go finish your race.
约书亚 我们还有两辆车在角逐名次
Joshua, we still got two cars in the mix.
我们得协同作战
Then we've got a team.
一旦红灯熄灭
Once those red lights go out,
这将是一场疯狂的冲刺赛
this will be an absolute sprint to the finish.
梅奔和法拉利排位占优
Position advantage to Mercedes and Ferrari.
APX GP车队轮胎占优
Tire advantage to APX GP.
叫JP跟着我
Tell JP to follow my lead.
约书亚 桑尼叫你跟着他
Joshua, Sonny says to follow him.
跟? 他在我后面啊
Follow? He's behind me.
-无耻之徒  -就是这样 跟紧了
-Cheeky bastard.  -That's it. Stay with me.
他在给你提供尾流 跟上去
He's giving you a tow. Take it.
必须的
All the way.
加油 小子 上啊 加油
Come on, kid. Get it. Come on!
海耶斯充当诱饵
Hayes plays the decoy,
皮尔斯瞬间超过勒克莱尔
and Pearce rockets past Leclerc
来到了第二位
and up into second.
勒克莱尔有被桑尼·海耶斯超过的危险
And Leclerc's in danger from Sonny Hayes.
桑尼绕到外线
Round the outside,
来到了第三
he's up into P3.
完美的团队配合
Perfect teamwork.
海耶斯和皮尔斯配合得天衣无缝
Hayes and Pearce working together,
就像赛道上的芭蕾舞
it's like racing ballet.
精彩绝伦
It's a beautiful sight,
但现在他们锁定了
but now their sights
领跑的汉密尔顿
on the race leader, Lewis Hamilton.
是的 还记得我吗?
Yeah! Remember me?
加油 兄弟们 冲啊
Come on, boys. Send it!
他们为什么不超车?
Why didn't they overtake?
谁先进攻 刘易斯就会防谁
Lewis will defend whichever car attacks first.
-但他们俩不能等  -必须有人牺牲
-But they both can't wait.  -Someone has to sacrifice.
二对一
Two onto one,
所有的压力都落在了汉密尔顿肩上
and all the pressure is on Lewis Hamilton
因为APX GP车队是团队作战
as APX work as a pack.
去赢下比赛吧 小子
Go win it, kid.
海耶斯率先发难
Hayes makes the first move.
汉密尔顿防守
Hamilton defends.
皮尔斯猛攻
Pearce attacks.
皮尔斯冲到了领跑位
And Pearce has P1.
-厉害  -太好了...
1Yes!  -Yes, yes!
短兵相接、毫厘不让
Toe-to-toe, wheel-to-wheel,
这是赛季收官站的精彩绝伦的比赛
this is epic racing to finish off the season.
桑尼·海耶斯和汉密尔顿的纠缠还没结束
And Sonny Hayes and Lewis Hamilton aren't done yet.
汉密尔顿攻击桑尼·海耶斯
Hamilton, on Sonny Hayes.
碰上了
There's contact!
汉密尔顿超了过去
And through goes Hamilton.
-好...  -加油
-Yes, yes!  -Come on!
Yes!
太好了
各位 快说 桑尼在哪?他能完赛吗?
Guys, talk to me. Where's Sonny? Can he finish?
还有一圈 JP 汉密尔顿从不认输
One more lap, JP. Hamilton never backs down.
桑尼能完赛吗?
Can Sonny finish the race, man?
能 他在赛道上 小心汉密尔顿
Yes, he's on track. Just watch Lewis when he fights.
你在领跑位 别再冒险了
You're P1. No more risks.
那不可能
No such thing.
新手占据着最佳线路
The rookie holds his line.
不肯让步
He won't back down.
他要和七届世界冠军一决高下
He's here to fight the seven-time world champion.
发生碰撞了
That made contact.
领跑车手和汉密尔顿冲出了赛道
The leader and Lewis Hamilton are out of this race.
虽然一号弯处摇起了黄旗
Despite yellow flags flying at turn one,
但是比赛继续
this race will continue.
桑尼 加速...你在领跑位...
Sonny, push, push, push, push, push. You're P1! You're P1!
APX GP车队还差一圈
APX GP has only one lap to go.
问题是 他们的车能行吗?
The question is do they have the car?
我们的车手能行
We have the driver.
好耶 加油 桑尼
Yeah! Go on, Sonny!
什么情况?
What's happening?
他在飞翔
He's flying.
桑尼 你成功了 我们赢了...
Sonny, you did it! We won! We won!
Yeah!
我们赢了!
We won!
Yeah!
-天啊...  -我们赢了
-Oh, my God. Oh, my God.  -We did it!
谢谢...
Thank you. Thank you. Thank you.
厉害
Come on!
这意味着鲁本能再干三年 对吧?
Means another three years for Ruben, right?
对
Yeah.
那笔交易我们之后再确认
I guess we'll check back about that deal.
前提是你还在董事会
Presuming you're still on the board.
令人惊叹 令人屏息 难以置信
Breathtaking! Breathless! Incredible!
多么精彩的阿布扎比大奖赛
What an Abu Dhabi Grand Prix this has been!
多么伟大的胜利啊
What a victory as well!
毫无疑问
Absolutely.
这是一场跨越时代的竞赛
It's a race for the ages.
绝对的惊心动魄
An absolute thriller.
这位车手赢得了他的第一次大奖赛
And this man wins his first Grand Prix.
好样的
Well done.
他赛车30年了
It's been 30 years in the making.
车队在维修区的表现也极为出色
And the team did a brilliant job from the pit wall
当然 不能忘记皮尔斯...
And of course we can't forget Pearce...
嘿 你笑什么呢?
Oi! What you smiling about?
笑你
You.
我将来会赢下无数比赛 你至少该赢一场
I'm gonna win a million races. You should at least have one.
我们成功了
We did it.
是的 我们成功了
Yeah, we did.
Whoo!
不...颁给他
No, no, no, no. Give it to him.
No, no, no. Give it to him.
天啊 谢谢...
Oh, my God. Thank you. Thank you.
Let's go!
我爱你
I love you.
Yeah!
今天我们可以说...
Today we get to say...
-"我们是世界第一"  -"我们是世界第一"
-"We are the best in the world!"  -"We are the best in the world!"
约书亚
Joshua.
如果你考虑为其他车队效力
If you were ever to consider to drive somewhere else,
你知道该去哪找我
you know where to find me.
谢了 托托 但我对现车队很满意
Thanks, Toto, but I'm happy where I am.
恭喜
Congratulations.
这就对了 宝贝 让他们等去吧
Yeah, baby! Let them wait!
让他们等去吧
Let them wait!
奖杯啊
The cup!
凯特 你造了辆火星车
Kate, you built a hell of a car.
又有一场我不知道的比赛吗?
Another race I don't know about?
在某个地方吧
Somewhere.
能比这场更精彩?
That beats this?
对
Yeah.
我本想说:"后会有期"
I wanted to say, "See you down the road,"
不过要用更有诗意的方式说
but in a way that was more poetic.
所以...
So...
后会有期?
Can I see you down the road?
好
Yes.
这个吻要好好品味到下次见面
Hang on to that until then.
好
Okay.
还有 开快点
And drive fast.
你要去哪?
And where do you think you're going?
别担心我 去庆祝吧
Don't worry about me. Go celebrate.
可你要去哪?
But you're off to where?
还有几条恶龙要屠呢
You know, couple more dragons to slay.
现在这是你的车队了
It's your team now.
一直都是我的车队
It was always my team.
我会看着你的
I'll be watching.
回头见 拽小子
See you around, swan.
诚邀车手
巴哈1000
你好
Hello!
Buenas
听说你们在找车手
I'm told you're looking for a driver.
你叫什么名字?
What's your name?
桑尼·海耶斯
Sonny Hayes.
你开过巴哈越野赛吗?
Have you ever driven Baja?
没有
Nope.
我们给不了太多钱
We can't pay much.
钱不是重点
Not about the money.
那重点是什么?
So what is it about?
本字幕由RN原创制作 禁止商用